<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://www.inmytrees.co.za/2</id>
    <title>AI Summary</title>
    <updated>2024-10-16T17:14:59.998Z</updated>
    <generator>ai-rss</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.inmytrees.co.za/2"/>
    <subtitle>AI Summary</subtitle>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[jamesql: An in-memory NoSQL database implemented in Python]]></title>
        <id>14804</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/capjamesg/jamesql"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T17:07:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[jamesql: An in-memory NoSQL database implemented in Python]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>python
from jamesql import JameSQL</p><br/>
<p>index = JameSQL.load()</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/hask9t">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>github.com by capjamesg</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T17:07:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Suspicious of Success]]></title>
        <id>14803</id>
        <link href="https://buttondown.com/hillelwayne/archive/be-suspicious-of-success/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:52:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be Suspicious of Success]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from <a href="https://buttondown.com/hillelwayne/archive/be-suspicious-of-success/">Buttondown</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Successful software is buggy software.  </p><br/>
<p>You should be suspicious if [the model checker] does not find a violation of a liveness property... you should also be
suspicious if [it] finds no errors when checking safety properties. This is specifically in the context of
model-checking a formal specification, but it&#39;s a widely applicable software principle. It&#39;s not enough for a program to
work, it has to work for the right reasons. Code working for the wrong reasons is code that&#39;s going to break when you
least expect it.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/bwjdbp">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>buttondown.com via JoelMcCracken</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:52:22.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned from Making the Python Back End for My New Webapp]]></title>
        <id>14796</id>
        <link href="https://youtubetranscriptoptimizer.com/blog/02_what_i_learned_making_the_python_backend_for_yto"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T15:08:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned from Making the Python Back End for My New Webapp]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a summary from <a href="https://youtubetranscriptoptimizer.com/blog/02_what_i_learned_making_the_python_backend_for_yto">YouTube Transcript
Optimizer</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>I stumbled onto the idea for this app by seeing how much time my wife, who is a YouTube creator who makes videos about
learning music theory, spent preparing additional materials to give to her Patreon supporters as an extra &quot;thank you&quot;
for supporting her videos. While it would be nice for her to have really good, accurate exact transcripts of her
videos, what I thought could be a lot more valuable would be if I could somehow generate really polished written
documents, formatted nicely in markdown, that conveyed the same basic information, but in a way that sounded more like
a real written article or chapter from a book. And I soon realized that, once you had that &quot;optimized document,&quot; you
could then use that to generate other useful things such as quizzes...  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859968">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>eigenvalue</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T15:08:56.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The University of Michigan Doubled Down on DEI What Went Wrong?]]></title>
        <id>14795</id>
        <link href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/16/magazine/dei-university-michigan.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:14:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The University of Michigan Doubled Down on DEI What Went Wrong?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from The New York Times:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>In 2022, the University of Michigan doubled down on its commitment to diversity, equity and inclusion. It was an
extraordinary moment for a school that had long been at the center of America&#39;s culture wars over affirmative action.
But just as it was preparing to unveil its new DEI strategy -- which included hiring hundreds more staff members,
expanding programs aimed at underrepresented students and investing millions in scholarships -- the Supreme Court
struck down race-conscious admissions policies nationwide.  </p><br/>
<p>Suddenly, Michigan&#39;s ambitious plans were illegal. And yet they continued anyway: The university forged ahead with many
initiatives that would have required consideration of race or ethnicity even after doing so became unconstitutional.
This decision has led to lawsuits against Michigan by conservative groups who argue that it is still using racial
preferences in violation of federal law.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41860855">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>tysone</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:14:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winamp deletes entire GitHub source code repo after a rocky few weeks]]></title>
        <id>14794</id>
        <link href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/winamp-really-whips-open-source-coders-into-frenzy-with-its-source-release/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:34:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Winamp deletes entire GitHub source code repo after a rocky few weeks]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Winamp has deleted its entire GitHub source code repository less than a month after posting it, following backlash from the open-source community over its restrictive licensing terms and concerns about proprietary code being included in the release. Ars Technica reports:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Winamp, through its Belgian owner Llama Group, posted the source for its &quot;Legacy Player Code&quot; on September 24 so that developers could &quot;contribute their expertise, ideas, and passion to help this iconic software evolve.&quot; Less than a month later,
that repository has been entirely deleted, after it either bumped up against or broke its strange hodgepodge of code licenses,
seemingly revealed the source code for other non-open software packages, and made a pretty bad impression on the open-source
community... Justin Frankel <a href="https://www.justinfrankel.com/faq#can-i-contribute-to-the-winamp-code">said</a> on his Q&amp;A site
about contributing to the code. Frankel responded that, even if he had some desire, the license terms &quot;are completely absurd
in the way they are written.&quot; Even taking them &quot;as they are likely intended,&quot; Frankel wrote,</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41861056">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>dangle1</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:34:15.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ArchiveBox is evolving: the future of self-hosted internet archives]]></title>
        <id>14793</id>
        <link href="https://docs.sweeting.me/s/archivebox-plugin-ecosystem-announcement"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:18:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ArchiveBox is evolving: the future of self-hosted internet archives]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Big changes are coming to <a href="https://archivebox.io/">ArchiveBox</a>, a self-hosted internet archiving tool, according to an
<a href="https://docs.sweeting.me/s/archivebox-plugin-ecosystem-announcement">announcement</a> from its developers. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>ArchiveBox v0.8 is shaping up to be the biggest release in the project&#39;s history. We&#39;ve completely re-architected the
internals for speed and performance, and we&#39;ve opened up access to allow for a new plugin ecosystem to provide
community-supported features...  </p><br/>
<p>Here’s just a taste of some of the first plugins that will be provided: yt-dlp for video, audio, subtitles, from
Youtube, Soundcloud, YouKu, and more; papers-dl for automatic download of scientific paper PDFs when DOI numbers are
seen; gallery-dl to download photo galleries from Flickr, Instagram, and more; readability for article text extraction
to .txt,.md,.epub; ai to send page screenshot + text w/ a custom prompt to an LLM + save the response; webhooks trigger any external API,
ping Slack,... etc. whenever some results are saved...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41860909">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>nikisweeting</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:18:39.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Rust is taking the data engineering world by storm]]></title>
        <id>14792</id>
        <link href="https://kerkour.com/rust-data-engineering"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:21:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Rust is taking the data engineering world by storm]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from Kerkour:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Rust is taking the data engineering world by storm. The language&#39;s unique combination of performance, safety, and
concurrency makes it an ideal choice for building robust and efficient data pipelines. As organizations increasingly
rely on data-driven decision-making, the demand for reliable and scalable data infrastructure has never been greater.
This is where Rust shines.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41860940">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>zishha1b0njq</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:21:46.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital River Runs Dry]]></title>
        <id>14791</id>
        <link href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1638251/digital-river-runs-dry?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital River Runs Dry]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Digital River has not paid numerous merchants since midsummer for software and digital products they sold through its MyCommerce
platform. &quot;After over 20 years of partnership with Digital River, <a href="https://www.traction-software.co.uk/index.html">Traction Software Ltd</a>
has been left feeling as though we’ve been &#39;rug pulled,&#39;&quot; Lee Midgley, managing director of Traction Software, told <em>The Register</em>.
&quot;For the past three months, we’ve experienced a complete halt in software sales revenue payments with no support, no direct contact,
and only additional terms and conditions designed to delay resolution and extract more money from us.&quot;<br>\n<br>Astonishingly, Digital River continued to take sales from our loyal customers until we removed them from the order system. It now
appears they have no intention of making payments and may be entering a liquidation process under a new CEO who has been involved
in similar situations before.&quot; The new CEO, Barry Kasoff, was first noted on the e-commerce biz website <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20240804174234/https://www.digitalriver.com/about-us/">in August</a>. Kasoff is also listed as the <a href="https://www.realizationservices.com/president-barry-l-kasoff">president of Realization Services</a>, &quot;a full-service strategic consulting firm specializing in turnaround management and value enhancement...&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://it.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1638251/digital-river-runs-dry?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:40:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Support ntfy.sh/web hook notifications?]]></title>
        <id>14790</id>
        <link href="https://lobste.rs/s/yb8l50/support_ntfy_sh_web_hook_notifications"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:36:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Support ntfy.sh/web hook notifications?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/yb8l50/support_ntfy_sh_web_hook_notifications">Lobsters</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>nfty.sh is a free and open source push notification server. It is self-hostable and works great in my experience. Since
Pushover is a paid application, I would like to see ntfy.sh supported in Lobsters for receiving notifications. As an
added benefit, this would double as a web hook since the link entered could be any endpoint that takes JSON.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/yb8l50">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>by jak2k</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:36:10.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best 4G mobile speeds in Gauteng’s biggest shopping malls]]></title>
        <id>14789</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/cellular/564852-best-4g-mobile-speeds-in-gautengs-biggest-shopping-malls.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:07:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Best 4G mobile speeds in Gauteng’s biggest shopping malls]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MyBroadband tested Vodacom, MTN, Cell C, Telkom, and Rain&#39;s 4G network performance in Gauteng&#39;s biggest malls <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/cellular/564852-best-4g-mobile-speeds-in-gautengs-biggest-shopping-malls.html">on October
9-10</a>.
The results were mixed:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Brooklyn Mall</strong><br>Vodacom was the clear winner in Brooklyn Mall, with an average download speed of 121Mbps and an average upload speed
of 26Mbps. Telkom scored second place, while Cell C and MTN recorded nearly identical download speeds. MTN recorded
double Cell C&#39;s upload speed in the mall.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Cell C took first place at Menlyn Park Shopping Centre:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Menlyn</strong><br>Cell C surprised us in Menlyn with the fastest average download speed of 85Mbps. MTN came in second place with
83Mbps and recorded higher upload speeds of 15Mbps compared to Cell C&#39;s 14Mbps.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Vodacom won at Mall of Africa; MTN dominated Fourways Mall; Centurion Mall saw a surprise win for Cell C; Eastgate had
another victory for that carrier as well. At Rosebank Mall (and The Zone @ Rosebank), it was a close race between those two,
with &quot;Vodacom, Rain, and Telkom all performed poorly.&quot; Sandton City also went to Cell C:</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=564852">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Wikus Steyn</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:07:51.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient High-Resolution Image Synthesis with Linear Diffusion Transformer]]></title>
        <id>14788</id>
        <link href="https://nvlabs.github.io/Sana/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:56:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient High-Resolution Image Synthesis with Linear Diffusion Transformer]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sana is a text-to-image framework that can efficiently generate images up to 4096 × 4096 resolution. It can synthesize
high-resolution, high-quality images with strong text-image alignment at a remarkably fast speed, deployable on laptop
GPU.</p><br/>
<p>Core designs include:</p><br/>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deep compression autoencoder:</strong> Unlike traditional AEs, which compress images only 8×, we trained an AE that can
compress images 32×, effectively reducing the number of latent tokens.</li>
<li><strong>Linear DiT:</strong> We replace all vanilla attention in DiT with linear attention, which is more efficient at high
resolutions without sacrificing quality.</li>
<li><strong>Decoder-only text encoder:</strong> We replaced T5 with modern decoder-only small LLM as the text encoder and designed
complex human instruction with in-context learning to enhance the image-text alignment.</li>
<li><strong>Efficient training and sampling:</strong> We propose Flow-DPM-Solver to reduce sampling steps, with efficient caption
labeling and selection to accelerate convergence.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a result,</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Sana-0.6B is very competitive with modern giant diffusion model (e.g. Flux-12B), being [20 times smaller and] [100+
times faster] in measured throughput. Moreover,
<a href="https://nvlabs.github.io/Sana/#sana-06b-is-deployable-on-laptop-gpu">Sana-0.6B</a> can be deployed on a <em>16GB laptop GPU,
taking less than one second to generate a [1024 x] [1024] resolution image</em>. Sana enables content creation at low cost.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859805">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Vt71fcAqt7</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:56:22.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTC Takes on Subscription Traps With 'Click To Cancel' Rule]]></title>
        <id>14787</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1550257/ftc-takes-on-subscription-traps-with-click-to-cancel-rule?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FTC Takes on Subscription Traps With 'Click To Cancel' Rule]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The U.S. Federal Trade Commission <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/ftc-takes-subscription-traps-with-click-cancel-rule-2024-10-16/">proposed a new rule</a> on Tuesday that would require companies to offer consumers an easy way to cancel subscriptions and memberships online, without
having to call customer service or navigate through multiple web pages. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The proposed &quot;click-to-cancel&quot; rule is aimed at preventing so-called subscription traps, where businesses make it easy for
customers to sign up but difficult for them to opt out of recurring payments. Such practices can lead consumers into paying
for services they no longer want or need, the FTC said in its announcement.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1550257/ftc-takes-on-subscription-traps-with-click-to-cancel-rule?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:01:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attacking APIs using JSON injection]]></title>
        <id>14786</id>
        <link href="https://danaepp.com/attacking-apis-using-json-injection"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T16:03:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attacking APIs using JSON injection]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a blog post:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>I wanna tell you a story from not too long ago, where exploiting a JSON injection vulnerability in Samsung devices could
trigger an attack chain that ended up with code execution on the device. It seems like the plot from some bad hacker
movie. But it wasn&#39;t. And it can serve as a lesson on how to abuse APIs who blindly trust the JSON in their payloads
far too much...  </p><br/>
<p>One of the features of <a href="https://danaepp.com/attacking-apis-using-json-injection#smart-hub">the hub</a> is the ability to
connect to smart cameras and process its livestreams, using the RTSP protocol. This code runs in the video-core
process, which is running as root. By sending a malicious POST request to the /credentials endpoint, it was possible
to modify the credentials used by <a href="https://danaepp.com/attacking-apis-using-json-injection#smart-hub">the hub</a> to
connect to remote servers and taint [...] The thing is, many of these devices live in constrained environments.
Typically running some sort of embedded Linux to drive code on system-on-chip (SOC) hardware. Which leaves its HTTP
servers (and supporting libraries like JSON parsers) somewhat constrained.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/caoesm">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>danaepp.com via jeremiahlee</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T16:03:32.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I started the day so optimistic]]></title>
        <id>14785</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20634464"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T15:49:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I started the day so optimistic]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shares a summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20634464">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>I started the day so optimistic. The sun was shining, birds were chirping, and my code was compiling without errors.
But then...  </p><br/>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/8g5q9hZ.png" alt="image">  </p><br/>
<p>-- Programmer Humor</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20634464">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/pwshguy</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T15:49:33.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The early days of peer review: five insights from historic reports]]></title>
        <id>14784</id>
        <link href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-03287-4"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:32:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The early days of peer review: five insights from historic reports]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UK Royal Society has more experience of peer review than most publishers, with the practice used by its journals for
nearly 200 years. Last month, the society unsealed more than 1,600 historic reports, dating from 1949 to 1954, and added
them to its archive. The reports include assessments of high-profile papers. The Royal Society&#39;s <em>Philosophical
Transactions</em> was the first journal to establish peer review...  </p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Some early referees&#39; reports have news about their holidays or what else they are doing,&quot; she adds. What do these and
other discussions show us about peer review? &quot;When peer review goes well, it is a system that allows authors to improve
the way they communicate their results. It is a unique moment of candid exchange between scientists where anonymity can
neutralize the discourse,&quot; Ferlier suggests.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Nature</em> rummaged through <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-024-03287-4">the archive</a> for insights into the evolution
of peer review:</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858331">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>rntn</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:32:09.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Un Ministral, Des Ministraux]]></title>
        <id>14783</id>
        <link href="https://mistral.ai/news/ministraux/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:31:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Un Ministral, Des Ministraux]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mistral AI has introduced two new models for on-device computing and edge use cases, called &quot;les Ministraux&quot;: <a href="https://mistral.ai/news/ministraux/">Ministral
3B</a> and Ministral 8B. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>These models set a new frontier in knowledge, commonsense, reasoning, function-calling, and efficiency in the sub-10B
category, and can be used or tuned to a variety of uses, from orchestrating agentic workflows to creating specialist
task workers. Both models support up to 128k context length (currently 32k on vLLM) and Ministral 8B has a special
interleaved sliding-window attention pattern for faster and memory-efficient inference.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859466">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>veggieroll</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:31:18.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Suspicious of Success]]></title>
        <id>14782</id>
        <link href="https://buttondown.com/hillelwayne/archive/be-suspicious-of-success/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T15:20:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Be Suspicious of Success]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a summary from Hillel Wayne&#39;s blog:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Successful software is buggy software. From Leslie Lamport&#39;s <a href="https://buttondown.com/hillelwayne/archive/be-suspicious-of-success/">Specifying
Systems</a>:  </p><br/>
<p>You should be suspicious if [the model checker] does not find a violation of a liveness property... you should also be
suspicious if [it] finds no errors when checking safety properties. This is specifically in the context of
model-checking a formal specification, but it&#39;s a widely applicable software principle. It&#39;s not enough for a program to
work, it has to work for the right reasons. Code working for the wrong reasons is code that&#39;s going to break when you
least expect it.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41860135">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BerislavLopac</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T15:20:08.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All software in EU under product liability from 2026]]></title>
        <id>14781</id>
        <link href="https://www.consilium.europa.eu/en/press/press-releases/2024/10/10/eu-brings-product-liability-rules-in-line-with-digital-age-and-circular-economy/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:58:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[All software in EU under product liability from 2026]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The European Union has adopted a directive to update its civil liability law, which will extend product liability rules to
software and digital manufacturing files starting in 2026. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The new law extends the definition of &quot;product&quot; to digital manufacturing files and software. Also online platforms can be
held liable for a defective product sold on their platform just like any other economic operators if they act like one.
[...] The directive will enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the Official Journal
of the European Union. Member states have two years to transpose the directive into national law.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859842">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>phkamp</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:58:48.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Finally Has a Color Kindle]]></title>
        <id>14780</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1416235/amazon-finally-has-a-color-kindle?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T15:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Finally Has a Color Kindle]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon is launching the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/16/24271632/amazon-kindle-colorsoft-specs-price-hands-on">Kindle Colorsoft Signature
Edition</a>, a color version of its
e-reader, for $279.99 on October 30th. The Verge reports:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>For years, Kindle users have asked Amazon to make a color version of its e-reader. Now, the company is finally
delivering: it&#39;s launching the new Kindle Colorsoft Signature Edition, a device that has a lot in common with the new
Paperwhite, except instead of black and white it&#39;s color all over...  </p><br/>
<p>The Colorsoft is based on E Ink&#39;s Kaleido technology but uses an entirely new display stack for Kindles, all the way
back to a newly designed oxide backplane that makes it easier for E Ink panel&#39;s tiny bits of ink to move around
quickly... All that display tech [...] allowed Amazon to introduce color without adding page-turn latency,
lowering the device&#39;s resolution, or hurting contrast on the display.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/1416235/amazon-finally-has-a-color-kindle?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T15:21:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solving the Maker-Taker problem]]></title>
        <id>14779</id>
        <link href="https://dri.es/solving-the-maker-taker-problem"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T15:30:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Solving the Maker-Taker problem]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from Dries Buytaert, founder and project lead of the open-source content management
system Drupal:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Recently, a public dispute has emerged between WordPress co-founder Matt Mullenweg and hosting company WP Engine. Matt
has accused WP Engine of misleading users through its branding and profiting from WordPress without adequately
contributing back to the project.  </p><br/>
<p>Although this post was prompted by the controversy between Automattic and WP Engine, it is not about them. I don&#39;t
have insight into their respective contributions to WordPress, and I&#39;m not here to judge. I&#39;ve made an effort to keep
this post as neutral as possible.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Buytaert argues that both companies are &quot;Makers&quot; who contribute significantly to open source software development,
while others in their ecosystem are &quot;Takers,&quot; who profit off those efforts without giving back enough in return.
He calls for more equitable systems across all open-source projects — including <a href="https://dri.es/solving-the-maker-taker-problem#drupals-approach-the-contribution-credit-system">a contribution credit system similar
to Drupal&#39;s</a> at other
open-source organizations like Wordpress:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Addressing the Maker-Taker challenge is essential for the long-term sustainability of open source projects. Drupal&#39;s
approach may provide a constructive solution not just for WordPress, but for other communities facing similar issues.</p><br/>
<p>By transparently rewarding contributions and fostering collaboration, we can build healthier open source ecosystems.
A credit system can help make open source more sustainable and fair, driving growth, competitiveness, and potentially creating thousands of new open source businesses.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/clz2na">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>dri.es via manuel</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T15:30:03.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Affairs crackdown in South Africa]]></title>
        <id>14778</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/government/565310-home-affairs-crackdown-in-south-africa.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:56:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home Affairs crackdown in South Africa]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Department of Home Affairs (DHA) is cracking down on corruption within its ranks and <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/government/565310-home-affairs-crackdown-in-south-africa.html">finalised 31 disciplinary
cases</a> between July and
September 2024, some of which resulted in criminal prosecution and dismissal. One such individual, Mogale Raseone, is
set to have his trial start on 6 November. He is facing charges of fraud after being dismissed from the DHA in 2023 for
manipulating department systems to fraudulently administer immigration for foreign nationals.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>In a statement,
<a href="https://www.dha.gov.za/index.php/statements-speeches/1830-within-three-months-home-affairs-disciplines-31-errant-officials-and-prosecutes-two-others-with-more-arrests-on-the-way">the department</a>
said the crackdown reflects its commitment to eradicating maladministration. It notes that officials faced charges for
violating the Citizen and Immigration Acts and irregularly recruiting new staff, with eight cases coming out of the Free
State and six out of KwaZulu-Natal. &quot;We have zero tolerance for unethical conduct or corruption,&quot; said DHA Minister Leon
Schreiber. &quot;As our accelerated action against errant conduct demonstrates, officials who fail to heed this message will soon find themselves out of Home Affairs and on their way to prison.&quot;</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Another official, Dora Ncube, is awaiting her day in court. The suspended Border Management Authority official was arrested<br>for allegedly trying to smuggle six foreign nationals into South Africa in Beitbridge.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565310">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Illidge</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:56:51.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supercharge the One Person Framework with SQLite]]></title>
        <id>14777</id>
        <link href="https://fractaledmind.github.io/2024/10/16/sqlite-supercharges-rails/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:50:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Supercharge the One Person Framework with SQLite]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a summary from Fractaled Mind:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>My name is Stephen Margheim, or you might know me as @fractaledmind on Twitter, and today I want to show you how
Rails 8 and SQLite together supercharge Rails as the &quot;one-person framework.&quot; I want to offer a vision of building
applications that have all of this power, but are this lean and this simple. Because, believe it or not, this is now
a viable application architecture, and one that can serve tens of thousands of users, if not many, many more. You see,
just like liquid methane and liquid oxygen in a rocket,</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858018">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>amalinovic</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:50:43.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon refreshes its monochrome Kindle lineup, including a bigger Paperwhite]]></title>
        <id>14776</id>
        <link href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/amazon-refreshes-its-monochrome-kindle-lineup-including-a-bigger-paperwhite/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:22:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon refreshes its monochrome Kindle lineup, including a bigger Paperwhite]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/10/amazon-refreshes-its-monochrome-kindle-lineup-including-a-bigger-paperwhite/">refreshing its entire Kindle e-reader lineup</a> today, including a major refresh to the pen-centric Kindle Scribe and a screen-size bump for the mainstream Kindle Paperwhite. The company also added its first color
e-reader, called the <em>Kindle Colorsoft</em>. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Going from most to least significant: The new Kindle Scribe&#39;s upgrades are mostly meant to make it a more paper-like writing
experience. It has a new textured screen coating, a white screen bezel that blends into the screen (we&#39;ve also seen this
deployed in tablets like the reMarkable Paper Pro), and a tweaked Premium Pen accessory with &quot;a new soft-tipped eraser&quot;
that feels more like an actual pencil eraser. Other improvements are being implemented in software, not hardware. A new
notetaking feature called Active Canvas allows you to draw in the margins of e-books, making text reflow around your notes
--previously, handwritten notes opened a separate pop-up, just like typed notes. A future software update will let you hide
and show those notes.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The <em>new</em> Kindle Scribe begins shipping on December 4 and starts at $399.99 — which is heftier than previous models but does include Amazon&#39;s Premium Pen accessory by default.</p><br/>
<p>The article continues with details about other devices:</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859345">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>thimabi</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:22:35.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Major online store shutting down in South Africa]]></title>
        <id>14775</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/business/565610-major-online-store-shutting-down-in-south-africa.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:40:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major online store shutting down in South Africa]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jumia Technologies, the owner of Zando, plans to shut down its South African online fashion store at the end of 2024 as it shifts
focus to other markets. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>According to a statement from the company, Jumia is cutting costs to reach profitability. This includes cutting jobs,
exiting the food delivery space, and eliminating delivery services not related to its e-commerce business. &quot;Jumia
Technologies, a leading e-commerce platform in Africa, today announced the planned closure of its operations in South
Africa, operating under the brand name Zando,&quot; it said.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565610">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Illidge</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:40:13.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Douglas Hofstadter on Lisp (1983)]]></title>
        <id>14774</id>
        <link href="https://gist.github.com/jackrusher/5139396"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:44:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Douglas Hofstadter on Lisp (1983)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Douglas Hofstadter&#39;s 1983 introduction to Lisp, <a href="https://gist.github.com/jackrusher/5139396">reprinted in his book
<em>Metamagical Themas</em></a>, is a charming and idiosyncratic tour of the
programming language that has been used for decades in artificial intelligence research. From the article:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>In previous columns I have written quite often about the field of artificial intelligence -- the search for ways to
program computers so that they might come to behave with flexibility, common sense, insight, creativity, self awareness,
humor, and so on. The quest for AI started in earnest over two decades ago... One thing that is nearly unanimous is
the choice of programming language. Most AI research efforts are carried out in a language called &quot;Lisp&quot;. (The name
is not quite an acronym; it stands for &quot;list processing&quot;.)  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858975">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eric_WVGG</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:44:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hell Freezes over as AMD and Intel Come Together for x86 – ServeTheHome]]></title>
        <id>14773</id>
        <link href="https://www.servethehome.com/hell-freezes-over-amd-and-intel-come-together-ocp/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:28:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hell Freezes over as AMD and Intel Come Together for x86 – ServeTheHome]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Intel and AMD have announced a new x86 advisory board to support x86 customers, with the goal of enabling consistency and
accelerating time-to-market for the x86 ecosystem. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The advisory group aims to unite industry leaders to shape the future of x86 and foster developer innovation through a
more unified set of instructions and architectural interfaces. This initiative will enhance compatibility,
predictability and consistency across x86 product offerings. To achieve this, the group will solicit technical input from
the x86 hardware and software communities on essential functions and features. Collaboration will facilitate the creation
of consistent and compatible implementations of key x86 architectural features and programming models, extending across
all sectors -- including data centers, cloud, client, edge [and] embedded devices -- ultimately delivering downstream
benefits to customers.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858304">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>rbanffy</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:28:52.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Joins Push For Nuclear Power To Meet Data Center Demand]]></title>
        <id>14772</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/144210/amazon-joins-push-for-nuclear-power-to-meet-data-center-demand?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Joins Push For Nuclear Power To Meet Data Center Demand]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has joined Microsoft in pursuing nuclear power to meet the energy demands of its data centers, <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/amazoncom-joins-push-nuclear-power-meet-data-center-demand-2024-10-16/">Reuters
reports</a>
(Warning: paywall):</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Amazon&#39;s cloud computing unit is working with a startup called X-Energy on developing the nuclear power technology
called small modular reactors (SMRs), according to an internal document seen by Reuters. The two companies are also
exploring building SMR plants near Amazon data centers, said the document dated July 31 and titled &quot;X-Energy - AWS
Partnership Overview.&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>An Amazon spokesperson confirmed that it was collaborating with X-Energy but declined to comment further. A spokesman at
X-Energy did not respond immediately to requests for comment.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/144210/amazon-joins-push-for-nuclear-power-to-meet-data-center-demand?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>msmash</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:40:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></title>
        <id>14770</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20630440"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Positive Intentions has <a href="https://positive-intentions.com/blog/qr-codes-as-a-data-channel">a blog post about using QR codes as a data
channel</a> in its decentralized chat app. The demo is
<a href="https://chat.positive-intentions.com/#/qr">here</a>.  </p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>We use JavaScript-based QR technology for offline data exchange and the innovative potential of this experimental
approach, which allows users to share files without an internet connection or centralized server.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20630440">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/xoron</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:01:39.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></title>
        <id>14769</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20630443"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Positive Intentions has a <a href="https://positive-intentions.com/blog/qr-codes-as-a-data-channel">blog post about using QR codes as a data
channel</a> in its decentralized chat app. The demo is
a bit clunky, but you can try it out at <a href="https://chat.positive-intentions.com/#/qr">chat.positive-intentions.com</a>.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20630443">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/xoron</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:01:43.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></title>
        <id>14768</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20630444"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:01:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Creating QR Codes with Javascript to use as a Data Channel]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Positive Intentions has a blog post about <a href="https://positive-intentions.com/blog/qr-codes-as-a-data-channel">using QR codes as a data
channel</a> in its decentralized chat app. The demo is
a bit clunky, but you can try it out at <a href="https://chat.positive-intentions.com/#/qr">chat.positive-intentions.com</a>.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20630444">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/xoron</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:01:47.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beware new WhatsApp scam in South Africa]]></title>
        <id>14767</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/security/565287-beware-new-whatsapp-scam-in-south-africa.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T14:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beware new WhatsApp scam in South Africa]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from MyBroadband:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>A MyBroadband reader working as a rental agent contacted us after experiencing a scam that involved an attacker
compromising communications between them and a client, placing both at risk of being defrauded. Their story provides
insight into how attackers are becoming increasingly sophisticated in targeting their victims and stealing millions from
unsuspecting people trying to do business with each other. In this case, the attack was a fairly typical attempt to
intercept and divert funds in a property transaction -- but with a WhatsApp twist. The agent told MyBroadband they had
arranged a rental viewing with a client, only to discover they had been communicating with <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/security/565287-beware-new-whatsapp-scam-in-south-africa.html">a middleman instead of
directly</a> with each other
as they thought.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>While viewing the property, the client mentioned that the agent had said the owner was willing to negotiate on the price.
This came as a shock to the agent, who could not recall the specific discussion. However, the client showed them the
WhatsApp conversation, which indicated that they had indeed discussed [...] Upon closer inspection, [the] agent realised
that it was not their contact number [...]. It was also soon realised that [the] agent had <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/security/541271-warning-about-email-scam-that-cost-property-buyer-r5-5-million.html">a different name</a>
to what [the] client had been told on WhatsApp. The agent then checked their WhatsApp conversation with [the]
client,* which again had <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2023/10/23/south_african_whatsapp_scam/">a different contact number than</a>
the one [the] client used.** This indicates that <em>[...+]</em>  </p><br/>
<p>The South African Banking Risk Information Centre (Sabric) provides several indications that your email address might have been compromised,
including:  </p><br/>
<ul>
<li>Complaints about spam being sent from your email address  </li>
<li>Emails not being received  </li>
<li>Missing emails  </li>
<li>Receiving large numbers of undeliverable or bounce messages for emails you did not send  </li>
<li>Not being able to log into your email account  </li>
<li>Seeing unknown emails in your Sent Items folder</li>
</ul>
<p>To further protect yourself from falling for <em>[...+]</em> scam, you should verify bank account details through multiple official channels.
This can include making phone calls or sending messages to numbers and email addresses listed on company websites or social media pages.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565287">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Puchert</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T14:00:53.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling with Apple Vision Pro]]></title>
        <id>14766</id>
        <link href="https://azadux.blog/2024/10/08/traveling-with-apple-vision-pro/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:48:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling with Apple Vision Pro]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Vision Pro has quickly become an essential item that I take onto every flight. It’s a fantastic device to travel with—Be it by train or by plane, it offers an unparalleled opportunity to selectively tune out your environment and sink into an engaging activity like watching a movie or just working on your laptop. In this blog post, I’ll outline what I’ve learned about the Vision Pro while traveling, explain some of the functionality, shine light onto its drawbacks, as well as assess how it fares against solutions like a phone or a laptop.</p><br/>
<p>For context, most of the traveling where I’ve brought my Vision Pro along has been on airplanes, but this applies to traveling by train as well.</p><br/>
<p><strong>Packing / Travel Setup</strong></p><br/>
<p>First and foremost, space in my suitcase or backpack while traveling is the most valuable commodity. Whenever I&#39;m packing for a trip,</p><br/>
<p>anything that adds unnecessary bulk to my setup is immediately discarded. For that reason, I highly recommend that you do NOT purchase</p><br/>
<p>the behemoth of the $200 Vision Pro &quot;travel case&quot; from Apple. It&#39;s unnecessarily massive and doesn&#39;t fit into ANYTHING. Avoid it at all costs unless you absolutely need a crazy amount of protection from the elements (but at that point,</p><br/>
<p>might as well buy a Pelican case!).</p><br/>
<p>My travel setup is super simple and minimal. To protect the front glass, I use the &quot;Vision Pro Cover&quot; that comes by default with</p><br/>
<p>the headset and on the inside, <a href="/2024/10/08/traveling-with-apple-vision-pro/#lens-protection">I use this affordable</a> generic VR lens protector cover to prevent anything from scratching [...]. With this setup, I&#39;ve not scratched or damaged</p><br/>
<p>the headset itself at all over [the] 5-10 flights I&#39;ve taken it on.**</p><br/>
<p><strong>User Experience</strong></p><br/>
<p>At airport security line, typically pull out my laptop and [Apple&#39;s] Vision Pro from my backpack. Thankfully, seems like [it doesn&#39;t look suspicious](/2024/10/08/traveling-with-apple-vision-pro/#airport-security-line) at all while being x-rayed as I&#39;ve not been questioned about it yet. The Vision Pro&#39;s 6DoF tracking system is built on a combination of IMU&#39;s + SLAM cameras (same as any other VR headsets).</p><br/>
<p>Unlike other VR headsets, however, it has native &quot;[Travel Mode]&quot;(<a href="https://azadux.blog/2024/10/08/traveling-with-apple-vision-pro/#travel-mode">https://azadux.blog/2024/10/08/traveling-with-apple-vision-pro/#travel-mode</a>) which accounts for using one in moving vehicles leading to massive drift &amp; tracking issues. As soon as it&#39;s put on when flying through turbulence it&#39;ll suggest turning Travel Mode ON via actionable notification; once activated it&#39;ll ignore IMU data entirely so horizon will be determined purely based upon orientation &amp; rotation of user&#39;s head instead — if their head tilts downwards then virtual apps/windows will tilt downwards too until they re-initialize manually after covering up lenses with hands briefly so cameras can lock back onto surroundings again without needing them visible anymore first before doing so themselves afterwards afterward...</p><br/>
<p>While wearing AirPods Pros are great because they offer top-of-the-line active noise cancellation but also adaptive/transparency modes allowing selective hearing depending upon situation...  </p><br/>
<p>[...]</p><br/>
<p>One caveat: during meals requiring eyesight coordination (like using fork picking food off plate):</p><br/>
<p>as soon user looks down towards food tracking often gets lost causing movie stop playing until looking forward again re-initializes tracking... Also field view more horizontal than vertical making eating challenging requiring fully tilting one&#39;s neck downward see what&#39;s happening below oneself rather than simply glancing sideways across table surface level instead! So usually remove headset eat meal return back afterwards later continue watching film uninterruptedly thereafter instead!**  </p><br/>
<p>Once started becoming more affordable foresee regular travelers buying them just have amazing in-flight entertainment systems since truly incredible experience altogether!</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41859012">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>tosh</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:48:51.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTC Announces "Click-to-Cancel" Rule Making It Easier to Cancel Subscriptions]]></title>
        <id>14765</id>
        <link href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/10/federal-trade-commission-announces-final-click-cancel-rule-making-it-easier-consumers-end-recurring"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:09:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FTC Announces "Click-to-Cancel" Rule Making It Easier to Cancel Subscriptions]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Federal Trade Commission today announced a <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2024/10/federal-trade-commission-announces-final-click-cancel-rule-making-it-easier-consumers-end-recurring">final &quot;click-to-cancel&quot; rule</a> that will require sellers to make it as easy for consumers to cancel their enrollment as it was to sign up. Most of the
final rule&#39;s provisions will go into effect 180 days after it is published in the Federal Register.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;Too often, businesses make people jump through endless hoops just to cancel a subscription,&quot; said Commission Chair Lina
M. Khan. &quot;The FTC&#39;s rule will end these tricks and traps, saving Americans time and money. Nobody should be stuck paying
for a service they no longer want.&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>The Commission&#39;s updated rule will apply to almost all negative option programs in any media. The rule also will prohibit
sellers from misrepresenting any material facts while using negative option marketing; require sellers to provide important
information before obtaining consumers&#39; billing information and charging them; and require sellers to get consumers&#39;
informed consent to the negative option features before charging them.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858665">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>pseudolus</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:09:04.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon buys stake in nuclear energy developer in push to power data centres]]></title>
        <id>14764</id>
        <link href="https://www.ft.com/content/00776191-b010-4104-add4-8dc430386911"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:32:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon buys stake in nuclear energy developer in push to power data centres]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has acquired a stake in nuclear energy developer <a href="https://www.x-energy.com/">X-Energy</a> as part of its strategy to power
data centers with small modular reactors, the Financial Times reported on Thursday. From the report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The investment is part of Amazon&#39;s broader push into nuclear energy, which it sees as key to powering its data centres
and achieving net zero carbon emissions by 2040. In September, Amazon ordered two X-Energy reactors for an undisclosed
location in North America.  </p><br/>
<p>[...] Small modular reactors are seen as safer than traditional large-scale plants because they can be built off-site,
transported and installed at their final destination. They also use less water than conventional designs.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858863">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>JumpCrisscross</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:32:36.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discord Rejects Role as 'Anti-Piracy' Partner; will no longer respond to DMCAs]]></title>
        <id>14763</id>
        <link href="https://torrentfreak.com/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-demands-rejects-anti-piracy-partner-role-241015/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discord Rejects Role as 'Anti-Piracy' Partner; will no longer respond to DMCAs]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Korean game publisher Nexon is using the U.S. legal system to address online copyright infringement. The company obtained a DMCA
subpoena that requires Discord to hand over the personal details of suspected pirates. While Discord has shared information in
the past, it doesn&#39;t plan to cooperate any longer, refusing to play the role of &#39;anti-piracy police&#39;. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Under U.S. law, rightsholders have an option to identify alleged copyright infringers, without directly having to file a
lawsuit. Instead, they can request a DMCA subpoena. These documents are typically signed by a court clerk and don&#39;t require
any judicial oversight. Specifically, they allow rightsholders to obtain the personal details of anonymous alleged infringers
through third-party service providers.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Discord&#39;s attorney wrote in July that &quot;acting as your copyright assertion partner is not one of them.&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>This strongly-worded letter didn&#39;t have the desired result, however. Instead of backing off, Nexon doubled down,
<a href="https://torrentfreak.com/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-demands-rejects-anti-piracy-partner-role-241015/">filing</a> (PDF) a motion
to compel at a Texas federal court late last week.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858955">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>isaacfrond</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:42:35.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talos Linux: API driven, Kubernetes operating system]]></title>
        <id>14761</id>
        <link href="https://talos.dev/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:43:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Talos Linux: API driven, Kubernetes operating system]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Talos Linux is a minimal, immutable operating system designed specifically for Kubernetes. It can run on cloud platforms,
bare metal, and virtualization environments. All management of the OS is done via an API -- no SSH or console access
allowed.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/lfib4g">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>talos.dev via jgarr</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:43:11.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Failure of the GPL (2009)]]></title>
        <id>14762</id>
        <link href="https://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1390172"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:50:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Failure of the GPL (2009)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David Chisnall <a href="https://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=1390172">casts a critical eye over the GNU General Public License (GPL)</a>, arguing that it has done more harm than good for the Free Software movement. He recounts how, in 1985, the Free Software Foundation was formed to promote software freedom as defined by four freedoms:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The freedom to run the program, for any purpose;<br>The freedom to study how the program works and adapt it to your needs;<br>The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor;<br>The freedom to improve the program and release your improvements (and modified versions in general) to the public so
that whole community benefits.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Chisnall notes that one of their tools is &quot;the GNU General Public License (GPL).&quot; But looking back he asks: &quot;has [the GPL]
been a help or a hindrance? And will it continue to be a help or hindrance in future?&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>He begins with an example of what he sees as its success — but also its failure:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>In 1985, NeXT purchased rights Objective-C...The C compiler at time was GCC, which was released under GPL. To avoid
restrictions this code, NeXT provided its front end as library that end users would link against GCC...This little
legal maneuver didn&#39;t work however, so NeXT was forced release code. Remember that an Objective-C implementation is two
parts: compiler runtime library...NeXT only required release its compiler code, not runtime library...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>&quot;Rather than admit they had worthless bit of code,&quot; writes Chisnall, &quot;GNU Project wrote own Objective-C runtime — and
this where things really started getting interesting.&quot; This led Apple developers working on GCC adding features like SIMD
support while simultaneously falling behind on supporting new features from GNU&#39;s branch.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;The story doesn&#39;t quite end there,&quot; adds Chisnall. More recently, Apple wanted integrate compiler more closely with IDE.
One nice things about Visual Studio is uses same parser semantic analyzer syntax highlighting error reporting as does for
code generation allowing much better feedback than get from editors completely separate two. Unfortunately for Apple,
GPL required either making XCode open source rewriting GCC...&quot;</p><br/>
<p>&quot;Fortunately,&quot; says Chisnall, &quot;Apple didn&#39;t have start from scratch...&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>But he argues this shows both sides of his argument:</p><br/>
<p>First we learn you don&#39;t necessarily get good results forcing people do things. NeXT Objective-C code contributed GCC\n<br>reluctantly, and never well maintained....end result better everyone.[...] Second thing remember sometimes having someone else&#39;s isn&#39;t actually good thing....If team had done this they probably would designed support multiple runtime libraries start ended up something lot more maintainable end.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/qew7qb">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>informit.com via calvin</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:50:29.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PAXI Revolutionises Business Deliveries – From Your Business to Your Customers’ Doorstep]]></title>
        <id>14760</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/industrynews/565576-paxi-revolutionises-business-deliveries-from-your-business-to-your-customers-doorstep.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:35:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PAXI Revolutionises Business Deliveries – From Your Business to Your Customers’ Doorstep]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In today&#39;s fast-paced commercial landscape, efficient parcel delivery is essential for businesses across all industries. Customers now demand swift, reliable delivery options, and companies that can&#39;t provide trusted courier services risk losing sales and falling behind competitors who can meet these rising expectations with speed and convenience.</p><br/>
<p>As South Africa&#39;s trusted choice for convenient, reliable, and affordable parcel deliveries,</p><br/>
<p><a href="https://www.paxi.co.za/contact#talk-to-us?utm_source=mybroadband&utm_medium=cpc&utm_campaign=paxiq1campaign&utm_camp_type=post&utm_content=awareness&utm_camp_id=284D3E97">PAXI</a> has been transforming the way everyday consumers send and receive packages. For businesses, their easy deliveries and returns solutions have been a game changer,
<a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/industrynews/565576-paxi-revolutionises-business-deliveries-from-your-business-to-your-customers-doorstep.html">allowing companies to effortlessly reach their customers anywhere in the country by simply using any of PAXI&#39;s network of over
2,800</a>
PAXI counterpoints nationwide. This means companies can increase their revenue by having the ability to reach customers in remote areas,
nationwide.</p><br/>
<p>PAXI&#39;s seamless business-to-door delivery offering goes one step further by giving businesses even more delivery options for their
customers to choose from, enhancing convenience and efficiency. This offering is tailored for companies that need to get their goods
directly to the door of their clients or third parties quickly and efficiently...</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565576">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Partner</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:35:04.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digital River runs dry, hasn't paid developers for sales since July]]></title>
        <id>14759</id>
        <link href="https://www.theregister.com/2024/10/15/digital_river_runs_dry_hasnt/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:03:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital River runs dry, hasn't paid developers for sales since July]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Digital River has not paid numerous merchants since midsummer for software and digital products they sold through its MyCommerce
platform. &quot;After over 20 years of partnership with Digital River, <a href="https://www.traction-software.co.uk/index.html">Traction Software Ltd</a>
has been left feeling as though we&#39;ve been &#39;rug pulled,&#39;&quot; Lee Midgley, managing director of Traction Software, told <em>The Register</em>.
&quot;For the past three months, we&#39;ve experienced a complete halt in software sales revenue payments with no support, no direct contact,
and only additional terms and conditions designed to delay resolution and extract more money from us.&quot; [...] The privately-owned,
Minnesota-based business appears to <a href="https://www.thelayoff.com/digital-river">have laid off</a> a significant number of employees,
presumably the result of what its UK subsidiary describes as cost reduction initiatives implemented in late 2022. Digital River,
Inc, owned by parent New York-based Danube Private Holdings II, LLC, has several subsidiaries including Digital River GmbH,
Digital River Ireland Ltd, and Digital River UK Limited. The company did not respond to a request for comment.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41856330">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>newaccount74</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:03:13.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My solar-powered and self-hosted website]]></title>
        <id>14758</id>
        <link href="https://dri.es/my-solar-powered-and-self-hosted-website"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:20:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My solar-powered and self-hosted website]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long-time Slashdot reader <a href="https://dri.es/my-solar-powered-and-self-hosted-website">Dries Buytaert</a> has been
experimenting with a solar-powered, self-hosted website running on a Raspberry Pi. The site is powered entirely by a
solar panel and battery on his roof deck in Boston. He writes:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>By visiting <a href="https://solar.dri.es">https://solar.dri.es</a>, you can dive into all the technical details and lessons learned
-- from hardware setup to networking configuration and custom monitoring. As the content on this solar-powered site is
likely to evolve or might even disappear over time, I&#39;ve included the full article below (with minor edits) to ensure
that this information is preserved.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>He explains how he set it up — including using an RS485 CAN HAT module for real-time data collection — then discusses its
energy use, cost savings, and environmental impact:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The tiny Raspberry Pi Zero 2 W at the heart of this project uses just 1 Watt on average. This translates to 0.024 kWh
daily (1W * 24h / 1000 = 0.024 kWh) and approximately 9 kWh annually (0.024 kWh * 365 days = 8.76 kWh). The cost
savings? Looking at our last electricity bill, we pay an average of $0.325 per kWh in Boston... Saving 9 kWh per year
reduces CO2 emissions by roughly <strong>4 kg</strong>, which is about the same as driving <strong>16 kilometers</strong> (10 miles) by car.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/injtfa">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>dri.es by Dries</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:20:40.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel spends more on R&D than Nvidia and AMD combined]]></title>
        <id>14757</id>
        <link href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/intel-spends-more-on-r-and-d-than-nvidia-and-amd-combined-yet-continues-to-lag-in-market-cap-nvidia-spends-almost-2x-more-than-amd"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:29:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Intel spends more on R&D than Nvidia and AMD combined]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Intel spent over $16.5 billion on research and development in 2023, more than AMD and Nvidia combined, according to <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/intel-spends-more-on-r-and-d-than-nvidia-and-amd-combined-yet-continues-to-lag-in-market-cap-nvidia-spends-almost-2x-more-than-amd">Tom&#39;s
Hardware</a>. But while Intel is still the biggest R&amp;D spender among semiconductor companies, it continues to lag behind them in market capitalization:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>[...] Apple spent around $27 billion or $29.915 billion on R&amp;D in 2023, which is more than AMD, Nvidia, and Qualcomm
combined.  </p><br/>
<p>Qualcomm is another high spender on R&amp;D. The company invests in system-on-chips for client devices like smartphones and
PCs, RF technologies, and fundamental research for next-generation radio technologies (6G, 7G, etc.). Perhaps the most
interesting part about Qualcomm is that among all the high-tech companies mentioned in this news story; it is the only one
with a working 5G modem.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858307">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>doener</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:29:04.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Africa’s new plan for China generator donation]]></title>
        <id>14756</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/energy/565349-south-africas-new-plan-for-china-generator-donation.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[South Africa’s new plan for China generator donation]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Africa&#39;s electricity and energy minister Kgosientsho Ramokgopa <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/energy/565349-south-africas-new-plan-for-china-generator-donation.html">explained</a> that the generators donated by China are not exclusively for load-shedding, but will also provide uninterrupted power at critical public
buildings, schools, and clinics in the country. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Instead, and in light of the extended load-shedding suspension in South Africa, the equipment will be used to keep the lights on during load reduction and when unforeseen circumstances, such as disruptive storms, cut power to an area.  </p><br/>
<p>Electricity and Energy Minister Kgosientsho took delivery of the second consignment of energy equipment from China in late August 2024, and the third consignment is expected to arrive soon. The equipment is being distributed to at least 500 public facilities.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565349">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Illidge</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:00:57.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discord Disputes DMCA Subpoena, Rejects Role As 'Anti-Piracy' Partner]]></title>
        <id>14755</id>
        <link href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/0632238/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-rejects-role-as-anti-piracy-partner?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discord Disputes DMCA Subpoena, Rejects Role As 'Anti-Piracy' Partner]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Korean game publisher Nexon is using the U.S. legal system to address online copyright infringement. The company obtained a
DMCA subpoena that requires Discord to hand over the personal details of suspected pirates. While Discord has shared
information in the past, it doesn&#39;t plan to cooperate any longer, <a href="https://torrentfreak.com/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-demands-rejects-anti-piracy-partner-role-241015/">refusing to play the role of &#39;anti-piracy police&#39;
(TorrentFreak)</a>.<br>\</p><br/>
<p>Under U.S. law, rightsholders have an option to identify alleged copyright infringers, without directly having to file a
lawsuit. Instead, they can request a DMCA subpoena. These documents are typically signed by a court clerk and don&#39;t require
any judicial oversight... When Nexon obtained a DMCA subpoena last October, Discord initially objected, deeming it &quot;overbroad and unduly burdensome.&quot; After the parties got together,
an agreement was reached <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.txnd.395421/gov.uscourts.txnd.395421.2.0.pdf">to confidentially disclose basic subscriber information related to 64 Discord User IDs</a>.<br>\</p><br/>
<p>Discord was clearly hesitant to cooperate but, faced with a motion to compel, it eventually chose <a href="https://www.torrentfreak.com/discord-shares-user-data-with-nexon-after-court-order-230628/">to do so</a>.... However,
<a href="https://www.torrentfreak.com/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-demands-rejects-anti-piracy-partner-role-241015/">going forward</a>, 
the company doesn&#39;t intend [...] In July,</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Discord sent a letter [to Nexon], informing the game company that it has no intention of cooperating with the latest
request, describing it as improper.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://yro.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/0632238/discord-disputes-dmca-subpoena-rejects-role-as-anti-piracy-partner?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T13:00:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumps - eager streams for rust]]></title>
        <id>14754</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/alexpusch/pumps_rs"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:46:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pumps - eager streams for rust]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from <a href="https://github.com/alexpusch/pumps_rs">GitHub</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>pumps-rs</strong>: Eager streams for Rust. If a stream allows water to flow down the hill, a pump forces it up.  </p><br/>
<p>The <a href="https://docs.rs/futures/latest/futures/stream/index.html">futures stream API</a> is awesome, but has unfortunate issues:</p><br/>
<ul>
<li>Futures run in surprising and unintuitive order. Read about Barbara battles
<a href="https://barbara.liskov.org/battles/buffered-streams.html">buffered streams</a>.</li>
<li>Prone to surprising deadlocks. Fixing the Next Thousand Deadlocks: Why Buffered Streams Are Broken and How To Make Them
Safer.</li>
</ul>
<p>This crate offers an alternative approach for rust async pipelining.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/a7fgiw">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>github.com by alexpusch</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:46:26.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GHC 9.12.1 (alpha 1) release notes]]></title>
        <id>14753</id>
        <link href="https://downloads.haskell.org/ghc/9.12.1-alpha1/docs/users_guide/9.12.1-notes.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:56:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GHC 9.12.1 (alpha 1) release notes]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>haskell</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>{-# LANGUAGE MultilineStrings #-}</p><br/>
<p>x :: String
x =
  &quot;&quot;&quot;
  This is a
  multiline</p><br/>
<pre><code>  string
</code></pre>
<p>  literal</p><br/>
<p>  &quot;&quot;&quot;</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/y2gpkx">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>downloads.haskell.org via jkarni</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:56:50.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla needs to come clean about HW3 before the word 'fraud' comes out]]></title>
        <id>14751</id>
        <link href="https://electrek.co/2024/10/15/tesla-needs-to-come-clean-about-hw3-before-the-word-fraud-comes-out/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:11:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla needs to come clean about HW3 before the word 'fraud' comes out]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The walls are closing on Tesla&#39;s claim that millions of its vehicles with Hardware 3 (HW3) computers will be capable of
unsupervised self-driving. [Electrek](/~article/2024/10/15/tesla-needs-to-come-clean-about-hw3-before-the-word-fraud-comes-out/)
reports:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Making a mistake is not a fraud. If Tesla really thought that it could deliver unsupervised self-driving to vehicles
equipped with HW3 and, at one point, it figured out that it couldn&#39;t, it&#39;s not fraud even though it used that as a
selling point for millions of vehicles for years. However, the moment Tesla figures out that it can&#39;t, it needs to stop
selling its Full Self-Driving package to HW3 vehicle owners and come clean to owners about what their vehicle will and
will not be able to do, like a robotaxi service.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858162">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>peutetre</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:11:52.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One possible housing crisis solution? Public housing for all income levels]]></title>
        <id>14750</id>
        <link href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/07/nx-s1-5119633/housing-crisis-solution-public-housing-mixed-income-maryland"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:06:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One possible housing crisis solution? Public housing for all income levels]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Montgomery County, Maryland has created a $100 million revolving fund that allows it to develop and finance its own
housing projects. NPR reports:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>It <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/07/nx-s1-5119633/housing-crisis-solution-public-housing-mixed-income-maryland">recently broke ground on</a>
Hillandale Gateway: 463 new mixed-income apartments that will be majority owned by Maryland&#39;s Montgomery County. It&#39;s
public housing. Although this is a far different model than traditional, federally funded housing for only the very
poor...  </p><br/>
<p>Montgomery County is a wealthy community, and it&#39;s long focused on housing for lower-earning families. Still, it hasn&#39;t
built nearly enough to keep up with demand, and the gap is growing. So a few years ago, it took an unusual step: It
created a $100 million revolving fund to dramatically ramp up construction... The public agency owns the controlling
stake in these apartments.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41858121">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>thehoff</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:06:28.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reinventing Core Data Development with SwiftData Principles]]></title>
        <id>14749</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20626941"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:04:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reinventing Core Data Development with SwiftData Principles]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20626941">Fatbobman&#39;s Blog</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>This article will explore how to apply SwiftData&#39;s way of thinking within Core Data, focusing on data modeling and
concurrent programming.  </p><br/>
<p>The goal is to make the development experience more enjoyable while maintaining compatibility with existing Core Data
projects.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20626941">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/fatbobman</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:04:25.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blender Survey 2024]]></title>
        <id>14748</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20627288"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:08:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blender Survey 2024]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blender Foundation <a href="https://www.blender.org/survey/">announced its first user survey</a> earlier this week, inviting users to share
their experiences and suggestions for the open-source 3D creation suite. &quot;The results will help us prioritize development
efforts in future releases,&quot; they said.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20627288">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://lemmy.zip/u/Blaze</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:08:41.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[sqlite3 WebAssembly &amp; JavaScript Documentation Index]]></title>
        <id>14747</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20627406"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:14:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[sqlite3 WebAssembly &amp; JavaScript Documentation Index]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SQLite developer Luis Norambuena has created a <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20627406">documentation index for the
WebAssembly</a> and JavaScript versions of SQLite. &quot;The documentation is organized in a
way that makes it easy to find information about specific features, functions, or APIs,&quot; he explains. &quot;This can be very
helpful when you&#39;re trying to understand how to use SQLite in your web applications.&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20627406">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/norambna</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:14:49.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starlink roaming cutoff survivors]]></title>
        <id>14746</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/broadband/565276-starlink-roaming-cutoff-survivors.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T12:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starlink roaming cutoff survivors]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many Starlink users in South Africa have continued to use the SpaceX-run service after it implemented a <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/broadband/565276-starlink-roaming-cutoff-survivors.html">60-day
continuous roaming use
rule</a>, which has made accessing
the service more cumbersome and expensive. In addition, one specialist importer has seen a surge in sales of Starlink
kits in recent weeks, which it attributed to positive political movements regarding the service&#39;s approval in South
Africa. These developments show there is strong demand for low-earth-orbit satellite Internet service in South Africa,
despite the country&#39;s communications regulator deeming it illegal.</p><br/>
<p>Starlink&#39;s roaming service has allowed people who managed to import a kit from an officially supported country by
themselves or via a specialised unofficial importer to use its fast and uncapped Internet for nearly two years.
While it cannot compete with cost-effective broadband solutions available in highly populated areas, like fibre,
fixed-5G, and fixed-LTE, Starlink is unmatched in connectivity-deprived rural areas. Aside from the Starlink kit, users
in South Africa only need a power source and a largely-unobstructed view of the sky in a southerly direction.</p><br/>
<p>MyBroadband&#39;s hands-on tests have shown the service can support fibre-like speeds and connection stability that outperforms older satellite Internet. While Starlink has been <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/broadband/536747-illegal-starlink-a-game-changer-for-south-african-farms-fishermen-rural-schools-and-cancer-screeners.html">illegal</a>
in South Africa since late 2022 due to not having required operating licences, [...]</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565276">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Hanno Labuschagne</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T12:00:45.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Internet Archive and its 916B saved web pages are back online]]></title>
        <id>14745</id>
        <link href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/the-internet-archive-and-its-916-billion-saved-webpages-are-back-online/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:09:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Internet Archive and its 916B saved web pages are back online]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Internet Archive has brought its Wayback Machine back online &quot;in a provisional, read-only manner&quot; as it continues to
recover from attacks that took the site down last week, founder Brewster Kahle said in <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/10/the-internet-archive-and-its-916-billion-saved-webpages-are-back-online/">a post
yesterday</a>.
The archive.org home page points users to the now-functional Wayback Machine but notes that other Internet Archive services
are temporarily offline. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Kahle said it was &quot;safe to resume&quot; the Wayback Machine&#39;s operations, but that it &quot;might need further maintenance, in
which case it will be suspended again.&quot; The Wayback Machine&#39;s &quot;Save Page Now&quot; feature that lets users capture a webpage
manually is currently unavailable. The related openlibrary.org book-preservation website was still offline today.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41857754">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Wingy</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:09:51.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel's bulky pager fooled Hezbollah]]></title>
        <id>14744</id>
        <link href="https://www.reuters.com/graphics/ISRAEL-PALESTINIANS/HEZBOLLAH-PAGERS/mopawkkwjpa/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:37:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Israel's bulky pager fooled Hezbollah]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from Reuters:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The batteries inside the weaponised pagers that arrived in Lebanon at the start of the year, part of an Israeli plot to
decimate Hezbollah, had powerfully deceptive features and an Achilles&#39; heel. The agents who built the pagers designed
a battery that concealed a small but potent charge of plastic explosive and a novel detonator that was invisible to
X-ray, according to a Lebanese source with first-hand knowledge of the pagers, and teardown photos of the battery pack
seen by Reuters. To overcome the weakness -- <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/israel-planted-explosives-hezbollahs-taiwan-made-pagers-say-sources-2024-09-18/">the absence of a plausible backstory for</a><br>[the] bulky new product -- they created fake online stores, pages and posts that could deceive Hezbollah due diligence,
<a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240321174411/https://www.electronicspower-batteries.com/">a Reuters review</a> of web
archives shows.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41857932">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>nabla9</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:37:36.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Police want the password to your phone]]></title>
        <id>14742</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20626507"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police want the password to your phone]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Police should never be allowed past your phone&#39;s lock screen without a warrant and specific proof of incriminating evidence,
argues <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20626507">Lee Duna</a> at programming.dev. &quot;The police have the right to search your
home, but they don&#39;t have the right to search through every single piece of paper in that home,&quot; he writes. &quot;They need a
warrant for that.&quot; From his article:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The same principle applies to phones. Your phone is an extension of yourself; it contains all sorts of private data.
If you were arrested, the police could not just take your phone and start scrolling through it looking for something
incriminating -- they&#39;d need a warrant first.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Duna argues that this principle has been upheld by courts in various countries around the world, including Canada,
Australia, New Zealand and Germany. In 2014 U.S. Supreme Court Justice John Roberts wrote: &quot;Our answer to the question
of whether law enforcement officers may conduct a warrantless search of cell phones seized incident to arrest is no.&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20626507">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://lemmy.nz/u/throws_lemy</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:43:15.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[It has been moved to another library 🎉]]></title>
        <id>14740</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20625718"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:09:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been moved to another library 🎉]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20625718">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Welcome to Programmer Humor! This is a place where you can post jokes, memes, humor, etc. related to programming!</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20625718">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://sh.itjust.works/u/babybus</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:09:54.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eskom se Push powering on]]></title>
        <id>14739</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/internet/565398-eskom-se-push-powering-on.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T11:02:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eskom se Push powering on]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Africa&#39;s beloved load-shedding notification app, Eskom se Push (ESP), has diversified its offerings while keeping
its core focus the same since load-shedding was brought to a halt in March earlier this year. Speaking to <a href="https://www.primediaplus.com/sa-approaching-the-longest-streak-without-loadshedding-on-october-18/">Cape Talk</a>, ESP co-founder Dan
Southwood-Wells said the app would still be available for South Africans should load-shedding return. &quot;First, we must
compliment Eskom on a job well done. We&#39;re really surprised that we were able to go through winter without any
load-shedding,&quot; said Southwood-Wells.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565398">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Puchert</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T11:02:43.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Commission concludes that X should not be designated under the DMA]]></title>
        <id>14738</id>
        <link href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/mex_24_5324"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T10:29:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commission concludes that X should not be designated under the DMA]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The European Commission has concluded that the online social networking service of X (formerly Twitter) should not be
designated as a core platform service under the <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/mex_24_5324">Digital Markets Act</a>
(DMA). From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Today&#39;s decision comes after an in-depth market investigation launched on 13 May 2024 following the notification by X
of its status of potential gatekeeper. Together with the notification, X also submitted rebuttal arguments,
explaining why its online social networking service should not, in its view, qualify as an important gateway between
businesses and consumers, even if X is deemed to meet the quantitative thresholds set out in the DMA. Following a
thorough assessment of all arguments, including input by relevant stakeholders, and after consulting the Digital Markets
Advisory Committee, the Commission concluded that X does indeed not qualify as a gatekeeper in relation to its online
social networking service, given that the investigation revealed that X is not an important gateway for business users to
reach end users.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41857503">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>robin_reala</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T10:29:34.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Floss/fund: $1M per year for free and open source projects]]></title>
        <id>14737</id>
        <link href="https://floss.fund/blog/announcing-floss-fund/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:02:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Floss/fund: $1M per year for free and open source projects]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Zerodha, an Indian financial services company, has launched a fund called <a href="https://floss.fund/blog/announcing-floss-fund/">FLOSS/fund</a> to provide $1 million per year in
financial assistance to free and open source software (FOSS) projects globally. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>This has been in the works for some time at Zerodha, where we have been developing financial technology products and
services built on an ever-growing FOSS stack. Without the high-quality FOSS projects that we have freely downloaded and
used to build our organisation, products, and services, we would not exist as we do today -- free as in both cost and
freedom. A significant portion of our success and growth is owed to FOSS...  </p><br/>
<p>And yet, funding and financial sustainability, the lack thereof really, has been an increasingly hot topic over the
last many years. Well, at least since cloud companies began making massive profits directly repackaging FOSS projects
built by hobbyists and communities. The rise of the &quot;open core&quot; model and the unfortunate license changes in many good
open projects recently, are clear signs of this growing turmoil.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41857032">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>joice</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:02:25.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't trust any VPN these days]]></title>
        <id>14734</id>
        <link href="https://blog.orhun.dev/cant-trust-any-vpn/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:51:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can't trust any VPN these days]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a blog post:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>On October 9th 2024, Discord was banned in Turkey due to various criminal allegations. This was an ongoing issue and
Discord apparently refused to share user data (IP addresses and content) thus the government decided to block the whole
thing altogether...  </p><br/>
<p>Today I&#39;m here to share what I have learned while trying to... you know. Find a way to use Discord again. Surprisingly,
this ban ended up being a positive experience for me.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Orhun writes about how he discovered his VPN wasn&#39;t working as intended when he tried using it after returning home from
an airport trip on that fateful day:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The most mind-boggling part of the problem for me was that I was able to use Discord via OpenVPN on my phone but not on
my computer. Whenever I try to launch the desktop app, it gets stuck at the loading screen with the error message I
shared above. To limit the scope of the problem, I also tried the website app directly, which resulted in <a href="https://blog.orhun.dev/cant-trust-any-vpn/#certificate-error">the certificate
error</a>. How does Discord know that I&#39;m still in Turkey!?  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>He eventually figured out &quot;I was using my ISP&#39;s DNS instead of <a href="/cant-trust-any-vpn/#dns-leak">my VPN&#39;s DNS</a>...&quot; He then had
to install some packages and add lines into his OpenVPN configuration file before finally getting everything back up and running:</p><br/>
<p># install Openresolv for managing DNS settings</p><br/>
<pre><code>pacman -S openresolv
</code></pre>
<p># install the script for updating DNS with OpenVPN (use your favorite AUR helper)</p><br/>
<pre><code>paru -S openvpn-update-resolv-conf-git
</code></pre>
<p>Then add [...]  </p><br/>
<p>script-security 2 # Allow script execution</p><br/>
<p>up /etc/openvpn/update-resolv-conf</p><br/>
<p>down /etc/openvpn/update-resolv-conf  </p><br/>
<p>And run [...]</p><br/>
<p>openvpn --config $HOME/.openvpn/client.ovpn  </p><br/>
<p>Boom, no more leaks! It goes through Frankfurt as expected! And I can use Discord again!</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41857290">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>orhunp_</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:51:30.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[South African students uncover massive grant fraud]]></title>
        <id>14733</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/security/565514-south-african-students-uncover-massive-grant-fraud.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T10:03:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[South African students uncover massive grant fraud]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two first-year computer science students at Stellenbosch University, Joel Cedras and Veer Gosai, have uncovered massive fraud
in the Social Relief of Distress (SRD) grant administered by the South African Social Security Agency (SASSA). After the
pair discovered that their and their friends&#39; R370 grants were being stolen, they investigated further and found a bank
account registered in Cedras&#39; name that had been receiving the grant every month. As <a href="https://groundup.org.za/article/we-discovered-flaws-massive-fraud-in-sassas-srd-system/">first reported on GroundUp</a>, fraudsters use unsuspecting
citizens&#39; identity numbers to apply for the SRD grant and receive the funds in bank accounts they have set up using the
same ID numbers.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;We had to call some banks, and eventually we found a bank account with my name, and they were receiving my R370 grant
every month,&quot; Cedras <a href="https://www.heartfm.co.za/news/sassa-cyber-crime/">told</a> Heart FM.  </p><br/>
<p>However, the issue extends far beyond a group of university students.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>To investigate further, Cedras and Gosai queried SASSA&#39;s application programming interface (API) for February 2005 at a rate of 700 records per minute. This was already a problem, as it should not be possible to query the agency&#39;s database at such speeds. The pair found that nearly 75,000 SRD grant applications were made for people born in February 2005. There were around 82,100 births that month,
working out to an application rate of about 91%. &quot;That&#39;s a very high amount that over 90% of people born in that month had an active Sassa application,&quot; sad Gosai.</p><br/>
<p>This indicates that not only are fraudulent applications being submitted to SASSA but many are also likely succeeding.
The students also conducted an on-campus survey of 60 other students they knew. Of the 60 respondents,</p><br/>
<p>58 had active SRD grant applications</p><br/>
<p>of which only two said they had applied for the grant themselves.</p><br/>
<p>Speaking to Heart FM,</p><br/>
<p>SASSA grant admission head Brenton van Vrede admitted</p><br/>
<p>that <a href="https://www.heartfm.co.za/news/sassas-grant-system-breached/">the organisation&#39;s grants system had been breached</a>.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;We do unfortunately have quite a lot of these cases,&quot; said Van Vrede. &quot;Some of the criminals have been apprehended.
My personal view though is that it is at a very low level... We do think there&#39;s a bigger operation behind this.&quot; He added 
[...]  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Van Vrede explained that many South Africans may find that an active application is already pending under their ID number when they attempt to apply for<br>the SRD grant.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;<strong>In such an instance</strong>, clients do need to then call our call centre, <strong>and then we have</strong> [...] facial biometric system<br>to verify true person behind ID number.&quot;</p><br/>
<p>Cedras and Gosai believe there is no straightforward solution to [...] crisis due scale crisis.** The pair said SASSA should re-verify every<br>grant application request additional details do so.** They also recommend organization reimplement its system from scratch.**</p><br/>
<p>However, note would leave many recipients out pocket.* Moreover, Cedras Gosai believe SASSA’s focus biometric verification undermines purpose SRD<br>grant designed accessible even people using devices lowest specifications.* The pair demanding answers from SASSA wants organization disclose cause scale crisis well who developed maintains SASSA SRD system what cost.*</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565514">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Illidge</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T10:03:38.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sustainable Building Effort Reaches New Heights With Wooden Skyscrapers]]></title>
        <id>14732</id>
        <link href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/0618259/sustainable-building-effort-reaches-new-heights-with-wooden-skyscrapers?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sustainable Building Effort Reaches New Heights With Wooden Skyscrapers]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long-time Slashdot reader <a href="https://ask.slashdot.org/~jones_supa">jones_supa</a> shares a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>At the University of Toronto, just across the street from the football stadium, workers are putting up a 14-story building
with space for classrooms and faculty offices. What&#39;s unusual is how they&#39;re building it -- by bolting together giant
beams, columns and panels made of manufactured slabs of wood. As each wood element is delivered by flatbed, a tall crane
lifts it into place and holds it in position while workers attach it with metal connectors. In its half-finished state,
the building resembles flat-pack furniture in the process of being assembled.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The tower uses a new technology called mass timber. In this kind of construction, massive, manufactured wood elements
that can extend more than half the length of a football field replace steel beams and concrete...  </p><br/>
<p>Today, <a href="https://www.ctbuh.org/resources/papers/4530-Journal2022_IssueI_StateofTallTimber+TBIN.pdf">the tallest mass timber building</a>
is the 25-story Ascent skyscraper in Milwaukee, completed in 2022. As of that year, there were 84 mass timber buildings
eight stories or higher either built or under construction worldwide, with another 55 proposed. Seventy percent of the existing and future buildings were in Europe, about 20 percent in North America and [...] According to estimates from researchers at Central European University,</p><br/>
<p>Ürge-Vorsatz says mass timber could be an important part [in combating climate change]. &quot;If you use bio-based material,
we have a double win,&quot; Ürge-Vorsatz says...</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/0618259/sustainable-building-effort-reaches-new-heights-with-wooden-skyscrapers?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't trust any VPN these days]]></title>
        <id>14731</id>
        <link href="https://blog.orhun.dev/cant-trust-any-vpn/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:51:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can't trust any VPN these days]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a blog post:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>On October 9th 2024, Discord was banned in Turkey due to various criminal allegations. This was an ongoing issue and
Discord apparently refused to share user data (IP addresses and content) thus the government decided to block the whole
thing altogether... I came home [and realized I can&#39;t use Discord at all, even with a VPN]. That&#39;s why I&#39;m writing this
blog post in the morning. Pain...  </p><br/>
<p>You might be asking, &quot;Hey Orhun, VPNs should work out of the box, what kind of a shitty setup do you have?&quot; and you are
absolutely right. I have my own VPN (😎) -- in other uncool words, I set up OpenVPN on a VPS and I have been using it for
a while without any issues... The most mind-boggling part of the problem for me was that I was able to use Discord via
OpenVPN on my phone but not on my computer. Whenever I try to launch the desktop app, it gets stuck at the loading screen
with <a href="/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#e58c8a828b8f868d84878b8780cb8185">an error message</a>. To limit the scope of the problem,
I also tried <a href="https://discord.com/">the website app</a> directly, which resulted in [the] certificate error.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/funtig">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>blog.orhun.dev by orhun</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:51:01.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E.W. Dijkstra Archive: On the cruelty of really teaching computing science (EWD 1036)]]></title>
        <id>14730</id>
        <link href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/transcriptions/EWD10xx/EWD1036.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:54:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[E.W. Dijkstra Archive: On the cruelty of really teaching computing science (EWD 1036)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long-time Slashdot reader <a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/transcriptions/EWD10xx/EWD1036.html">E.W. Dijkstra Archive</a> shares a
<a href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~EWD/transcriptions/EWD10xx/EWD1036.html">transcription of an 1988 talk</a> by the late computer
scientist Edsger W. Dijkstra, who argued that &quot;automatic computers represent a radical novelty&quot; and that only by
identifying them as such can we identify all the nonsense, misconceptions and mythology surrounding them.&quot; The second
radical novelty is that the automatic computer is our first large-scale digital device,&quot; he added.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>It is possible, and even tempting, to view a program as an abstract mechanism, as a device of some sort. To do so,
however, is highly dangerous: the analogy is too shallow because a program is, as a mechanism, totally different from all
the familiar analogue devices we grew up with... In the discrete world of computing there is no meaningful metric in
which &quot;small&quot; changes and &quot;small&quot; effects go hand in hand....  </p><br/>
<p>This second radical novelty shares the usual fate of all radical novelties: it is denied because its truth would be too
discomforting... I have no idea what this specific denial and disbelief costs the United States but a million dollars a
day seems like modest guess...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/1rjux4">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>cs.utexas.edu via Kchousos</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:54:13.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mullvad: macOS sometimes leaks traffic after system updates]]></title>
        <id>14728</id>
        <link href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/macos-sometimes-leaks-traffic-after-system-updates"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:37:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mullvad: macOS sometimes leaks traffic after system updates]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mullvad VPN has <a href="https://mullvad.net/en/blog/macos-sometimes-leaks-traffic-after-system-updates">discovered a traffic leak on macOS after system
updates</a>, which can be resolved by
rebooting the machine. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>In this scenario the macOS firewall does not seem to function correctly and is disregarding firewall rules. Most traffic
will still go inside the VPN tunnel since the routing table specifies that it should. Unfortunately apps are not
required to respect the routing table and can send traffic outside the tunnel if they try to. Some examples of apps
that do this are Apple&#39;s own apps and services since macOS 14.6, up until a recent 15.1 beta.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Mullvad says it&#39;s currently investigating further, but in the meantime users can check whether they&#39;re affected with some
terminal commands (detailed instructions at their blog).</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41856883">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>dulvui</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:37:23.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best smartphone trade-ins in South Africa]]></title>
        <id>14727</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/smartphones/565256-best-smartphone-trade-ins-in-south-africa.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:01:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Best smartphone trade-ins in South Africa]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shares a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>A comparison by MyBroadband shows that Samsung South Africa&#39;s online trade-in website offers the worst smartphone-for-cash
trade-in values among several major online trade-in outlets. A MyBroadband reader recently wanted to <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/smartphones/565256-best-smartphone-trade-ins-in-south-africa.html">trade in his
Samsung Galaxy S22 256GB before upgrading to a new
device</a>. Considering
Samsung&#39;s commanding market share in South Africa and its extensive aftersales support and footprint, he assumed he would
be able to get a fair price for his fully functional device. He was surprised that Samsung only offered him R2,000 in cash
for his device, despite it having no screen or chassis damage and being fully functional. This was an astounding R13,999 --
or 87% -- less than what he had paid for the phone in early 2022.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565256">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Hanno Labuschagne</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:01:06.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing a Type-safe printf in Rust (2020)]]></title>
        <id>14726</id>
        <link href="https://willcrichton.net/notes/type-safe-printf/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:58:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Implementing a Type-safe printf in Rust (2020)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a blog post from Will Crichton:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>I show how to use heterogeneous lists and traits to implement a type-safe printf in Rust. These mechanisms can ensure
that two variadic argument lists share important properties, like the number of format string holes matches the number
of printf arguments. Part of an ongoing series about type-level programming in Rust. Consider reading part one first!
All code in this note can be found in <a href="https://gist.github.com/willcrichton/1c4e7b8d0f5a2c9cb6bc3eebdffcfb36">this gist</a>.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Crichton&#39;s article was originally published on June 21, 2020.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/rgtvrg">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>willcrichton.net via bitfield</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:58:03.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing FLOSS/fund: $1M per year for free and open source projects]]></title>
        <id>14725</id>
        <link href="https://floss.fund/blog/announcing-floss-fund/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T09:07:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing FLOSS/fund: $1M per year for free and open source projects]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Zerodha, a financial technology company based in India, has launched <a href="https://floss.fund/blog/announcing-floss-fund/">FLOSS/fund</a>, which will provide $1 million per year to free and open source software (FOSS) projects. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>This has been in the works for some time at Zerodha[↗], where we have been developing financial technology products and
services built on an ever-growing FOSS stack. Without the high-quality FOSS projects that we have freely downloaded and
used to build our organisation, products, and services, we would not exist as we do today -- free as in both cost and
freedom. A significant portion of our success and growth is owed to FOSS, encompassing everything from programming
languages to operating systems, to databases, web servers, frontend frameworks, productivity tools, code editors,
and absolutely everything.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The fund aims &quot;to exercise goodwill,&quot; said Kailash Nadh (CTO @ Zerodha). &quot;It makes perfect logical sense for a business
that relies on FOSS...to support it.&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>&quot;At the very least,&quot; he added later in his post: &quot;a profitable business should allocate a tiny fraction of its profits
to support the projects it is directly reliant on.&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/f3pgi1">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>floss.fund via joice</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T09:07:49.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self Hosting Vaultwarden and Setting up SSL Certificates under Tailscale in Nixos]]></title>
        <id>14724</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20621218"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:33:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Self Hosting Vaultwarden and Setting up SSL Certificates under Tailscale in Nixos]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shares a summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20621218">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>I have been using pass but since I am experimenting with selfhosting and wanted to store passkeys inside my password
manager I wanted to selfhost Vaultwarden (a Bitwarden server implementation) server but I didn&#39;t want to expose it to
internet so I wanted to use my Tailscale network. So, I added required config to my Raspberry 5&#39;s Nixos config <code>services.vaultwarden = { enable = true; };</code> and now I needed an easier way to access it then with ip and port so
<a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-nginx-reverse-proxy-on-ubuntu-20-04">I needed</a> to setup a
reverse proxy like nginx, since I&#39;m using Tailscale [...] decided not to use MagicDNS].  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20621218">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://lemmy.world/u/alper_celik</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:33:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Since spring of 2023, the world has been warmer than climate models anticipated]]></title>
        <id>14723</id>
        <link href="https://e360.yale.edu/features/gavin-schmidt-interview"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:13:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since spring of 2023, the world has been warmer than climate models anticipated]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from Yale E360:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Since early 2023, the world has seen a steep rise in temperatures that scientists are struggling to explain. Our
contributor Elizabeth Kolbert talked with Gavin Schmidt, NASA&#39;s top climate scientist, about possible causes of the
warming and why experts cannot account for the heat.  </p><br/>
<p>About 18 months ago, climate scientists began to notice something strange. In March of 2023, global sea surface
temperatures started to rise. In a warming world, the seas would be expected to grow hotter, but the rise -- which came
at a time when the Pacific Ocean was in the neutral phase of the weather pattern known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/El_Ni%C3%B1o">the El Niño-Southern
Oscillation</a> (ENSO) -- was unusually steep. In April 2023, sea surface
temperatures set a new record. They did so again in May...  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41856738">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>orcul</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:13:11.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching old assert() new Tricks]]></title>
        <id>14722</id>
        <link href="https://blog.ngs-lang.org/2024/10/06/teaching-old-assert-new-tricks/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:22:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching old assert() new Tricks]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from a blog:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Many languages have assert(). This post describes how assert() is implemented in Next Generation Shell and how these
aspects/features are consistent with the rest of the language. Implied in the above is that the ideas below might not be
a good fit for assert() in your favorite language or framework.  </p><br/>
<p>Note that <code>assert(EXPR, PATTERN)</code> in NGS is same as <code>EXPR.assert(PATTERN)</code>. It&#39;s called UFCS.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/auvpvi">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>blog.ngs-lang.org by ilyash</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:22:40.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capitec blocks payments to cryptocurrency exchanges]]></title>
        <id>14721</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/cryptocurrency/565469-capitec-blocks-payments-to-cryptocurrency-exchanges.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T08:03:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Capitec blocks payments to cryptocurrency exchanges]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Capitec has blocked EFT and immediate payments to cryptocurrency exchanges from its smartphone app and business web
interface. The issue was first highlighted by Shiftly co-founder and CEO Carel de Villiers. When MyBroadband asked Capitec
about the change, the bank said it was an anti-fraud measure.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;Capitec is committed to protecting our clients from fraud, which is why we made the decision to block EFT and immediate
real-time clearing payments to crypto exchanges on our app and business web interface,&quot; a spokesperson said. &quot;We recognise
the increasing interest in cryptocurrencies and encourage users to utilise Capitec Pay as a secure alternative for
transactions.&quot; Capitec said it was actively working with crypto exchanges that have not yet integrated Capitec Pay to
expedite this process.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Ensuring the safety and security of our clients&#39; financial transactions remains our top priority,&quot; it said. This change came after Capitec announced that its app now communicates with its Fraud Center in real-time. It said the app will warn customers <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/cryptocurrency/565469-capitec-blocks-payments-to-cryptocurrency-exchanges.html#readability-page-1">and block payments in real time if any beneficiaries have reported or confirmed fraud against them</a>. For example,
even brand new bank accounts created at any institution will be blocked for all Capitec clients if there is confirmed
fraud reported against it. According to Capitec, it is the first bank to do real-time and on-the-wire interception and blocking of suspicious payments [...].</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565469">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Vermeulen</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T08:03:54.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Safety without Lifetime Parameters]]></title>
        <id>14720</id>
        <link href="https://safecpp.org/draft-lifetimes.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:45:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Memory Safety without Lifetime Parameters]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from a blog post:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>This proposal describes the implementation of a memory-safe reference type that does not use lifetime
annotations. The goal of the proposal is to:</p><br/>
<ul>
<li>Explore the viability of memory safety without lifetime parameters.</li>
<li>Explain the infeasibility of making legacy lvalue- and rvalue-references memory safe.</li>
<li>Address common objections to safety models that use lifetime annotations.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Read more about it at <a href="https://safecpp.org/draft-lifetimes.html">safecpp.org</a>.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/g8buij">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>safecpp.org via hunger</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:45:11.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Apple iPad Mini launched]]></title>
        <id>14718</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/hardware/565470-new-apple-ipad-mini-launched.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:17:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Apple iPad Mini launched]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apple has introduced a new iPad Mini featuring Apple Intelligence and fitted with the A17 Pro chip. The 8.3-inch device
boasts a Liquid Retina display and comes in four colours: blue, purple, starlight, and space grey. Its A17 processor has a
6-core CPU -- two performance cores and four efficiency cores -- and a Neural Engine twice as fast as the previous
generation of the iPad Mini. The chip is also equipped with a 5-core GPU, delivering a 25% increase in graphics
performance over the previous generation.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Apple promises all-day battery life and said the table will ship with its latest operating system, iPadOS 18...  </p><br/>
<p>Apple said [Apple Intelligence for iPad Mini will launch to customers in US English this month - October 2024]. These
features include writing tools that allow users to summarise, proofread, and rewrite their work. Siri will also be more
integrated into the functioning of the device, with increased language processing capabilities... On the back of the
device is a 12MP camera that can employ Apple Intelligence to remove shadows when scanning documents.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565470">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Puchert</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:17:22.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng regional winners for the 2024 Vodacom Journalist of the Year Awards announced]]></title>
        <id>14717</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/industrynews/565491-gauteng-regional-winners-for-the-2024-vodacom-journalist-of-the-year-awards-announced.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng regional winners for the 2024 Vodacom Journalist of the Year Awards announced]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The regional winners in the 2024 Vodacom Journalist of the Year Awards for Gauteng have been named with media in the
respective provinces celebrating their success across the competition&#39;s 12 categories. More than 1,200 entries were
received from journalists around the country as they shared examples of their best work from the past year.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;As we commemorate 30 years of democracy in South Africa, we are reminded of the importance of media as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fourth_estate">the fourth
estate</a> that is crucial to our democracy. Ethical, independent and critical
journalism holds those in power accountable and brings transparency to affairs that matter,&quot; said Takalani Netshitenzhe,
Director for External Affairs at Vodacom South Africa.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;Coinciding with 30 years of democracy, Vodacom South Africa celebrates 30 years of connecting South Africans and we are proud to be continuing our legacy of honouring excellence in journalism across a range of categories,
recognising some of South Africa&#39;s finest reporters and most newsworthy stories. Support for journalism remains paramount as
the sustainability of journalism creates well-informed and connected societies.&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565491">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Partner</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:42:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for submissions for a new CSS logo]]></title>
        <id>14716</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/CSS-Next/css-next/issues/105"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:13:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Call for submissions for a new CSS logo]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The CSS-Next project is <a href="https://github.com/CSS-Next/css-next/issues/105">looking for a new logo</a>, and has been collecting
community submissions on GitHub. &quot;We&#39;ve deliberated a few times about the logos now and have begun unanimously converging
on the submission by @itsjavi,&quot; writes collaborator Argyleink, adding that as of this writing, &quot;<a href="https://github.com/CSS-Next/css-next/issues/105#issuecomment-1740526688">the comment with itsjavi&#39;s
submission</a> has the most votes by far.&quot;<br>\n<br>Here&#39;s what it looks like:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p><img src="/user-attachments/assets/e71e7384-6bb1-46e5-8db1-db36973ed78a" alt="CSS Logo Proposal"></p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>&quot;Thank you @argyleink and awesome work @itsjavi,&quot; adds una (another collaborator). &quot;Maybe interesting to &#39;open source&#39;
figma, illustrator, ... files? Then people can make subtle variants, or add subtitles?&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>Argyleink responded that they would do so: &quot;we&#39;ve also got a working Codepen (but uses text-box-trim, so needs Canary or
Safari TP). Will share more official files and pens once all the dust has settled.&quot;</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/u300ns">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>github.com via sny</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:13:05.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MTN reveals Black Friday 2024 plans]]></title>
        <id>14715</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/black-friday/565412-mtn-reveals-black-friday-2024-plans.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:07:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MTN reveals Black Friday 2024 plans]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Black Friday 2024 is just over a month away, and while MTN isn&#39;t ready to announce its deals yet, the mobile network
operator <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/black-friday/565412-mtn-reveals-black-friday-2024-plans.html">told MyBroadband</a>
that it plans to offer deals on devices, data, and voice plans. The annual sales event will take place on 29 November
2024. MTN South Africa said it plans to hold an extended Black Friday promotion in 2024. It told MyBroadband that its
deals will be available for longer than just the weekend of the sales event.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;MTN can confirm that it will be participating in this year&#39;s Black Friday promotion,&quot; it said. &quot;Our customers can
anticipate great deals and value on selected price plans, devices, data and voice.&quot;  </p><br/>
<p>It added that it will soon communicate further details, including deals and promotions surrounding Black Friday.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565412">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Myles Illidge</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:07:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Self-Hosted Llama 3.2 with Coolify on My Home Server: A Step-by-Step Guide]]></title>
        <id>14714</id>
        <link href="https://geek.sg/blog/how-i-self-hosted-llama-32-with-coolify-on-my-home-server-a-step-by-step-guide"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T05:26:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I Self-Hosted Llama 3.2 with Coolify on My Home Server: A Step-by-Step Guide]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Raymond Yeh has a detailed blog post about <a href="https://geek.sg/blog/how-i-self-hosted-llama-32-with-coolify-on-my-home-server-a-step-by-step-guide">self-hosting Llama 3.2 on his home
server</a> using
Coolify, with a focus on enabling GPU acceleration using the CUDA toolkit:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The primary idea was to leverage my home server, previously gathering dust, to perform valuable tasks. Specifically,
I wanted it to host and automate AI-related functions. Additionally, this setup would provide a centralized location
to run Supabase for storing various data...  </p><br/>
<p>Setting up this environment was no small feat, but each step was a valuable learning experience...  </p><br/>
<p><strong>Installing Ubuntu 24:</strong> This was a breeze, requiring only a single reboot.<br><strong>Coolify Installation:</strong> The process was smooth thanks to the handy install script, which ensured most prerequisites
were met. A minor hiccup was resolved by running commands as root to avoid permission issues with the /data directory.
Configuring Coolify: Initially, setting the server as localhost prevented assigning a domain via Cloudflare Tunnel.
The fix involved adding the host as a second &#39;server&#39;. Moreover, configuring the tunnel and SSL correctly took time
but was crucial for security and functionality...  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855886">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>whitefables</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T05:26:35.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Section of Euclid Space Telescope's Map of the Universe Revealed]]></title>
        <id>14713</id>
        <link href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/063239/first-section-of-euclid-space-telescopes-map-of-the-universe-revealed?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T07:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First Section of Euclid Space Telescope's Map of the Universe Revealed]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first chunk of what will be the largest 3D map of the universe ever made has been <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/oct/15/euclid-space-telescope-3d-map-universe-first-section">revealed</a>, putting 14 million galaxies
-- not to mention tens of millions of stars in our own Milky Way -- on show in incredible detail. The Euclid mission,
launched in 2023 and run by the European Space Agency (Esa) with contributions from Nasa, sent its first snapshots in
November of that year and in May 2024. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The goal of Euclid is to enable the creation of a 3D map in time and space of the universe, in an attempt to elucidate
its evolution and, as a result, shed light on the mysterious phenomena of dark energy and dark matter that together make
up 95% of the universe.  </p><br/>
<p>The newly released data is a mosaic <a href="https://www.esa.int/Science_Exploration/Space_Science/Euclid/Zoom_into_the_first_page_of_ESA_Euclid_s_great_cosmic_atlas">of 208 gigapixels</a> and covers [1%](/science/exploration/universe/cosmic-mystery-dark-energy-dark-matter)* 
[of](/science/exploration/universe/cosmic-mystery-dark-energy-dark-matter). The completed map is expected to involve six
years&#39; worth observations and will take in a third [of](/science/exploration/universe/cosmic-mystery-dark-energy-dark-matter)
[the](/science/exploration/universe/cosmic-mystery-dark-energy-dark-matter) sky, with observations expected to capture billions
[of](/science/exploration/universe/cosmic-mystery-dark-energy-dark-matter) galaxies out to (10bn light years.)</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://science.slashdot.org/story/24/10/16/063239/first-section-of-euclid-space-telescopes-map-of-the-universe-revealed?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T07:00:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tell HN: The Wayback Machine is up, in read-only mode]]></title>
        <id>14712</id>
        <link href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41856008"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T05:56:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tell HN: The Wayback Machine is up, in read-only mode]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Wayback Machine is back online, albeit in a &quot;provisional, read-only&quot; state. The rest of Archive.org&#39;s services remain
down.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41856008">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>jfil</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T05:56:06.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safer with Google: Advancing Memory Safety]]></title>
        <id>14711</id>
        <link href="https://security.googleblog.com/2024/10/safer-with-google-advancing-memory.html?m=1"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T06:32:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safer with Google: Advancing Memory Safety]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google&#39;s security team has <a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2024/10/safer-with-google-advancing-memory.html?m=1">detailed its ongoing efforts to improve memory
safety</a> in the software it uses and
produces, including a two-pronged strategy that involves migrating existing codebases to memory-safe languages like Rust,
while also hardening legacy C++ code. From a report:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Error-prone interactions between software and memory are widely understood to create safety issues in software. It is
estimated that about 70% of severe vulnerabilities in memory-unsafe codebases are due to memory safety bugs.
Malicious actors exploit these vulnerabilities and continue to create real-world harm. In 2023, Google&#39;s threat
intelligence teams conducted an industry-wide study and observed a close to all-time high number of vulnerabilities
exploited in the wild. Our internal analysis estimates that 75% of CVEs used in zero-day exploits are memory safety
vulnerabilities...  </p><br/>
<p>This post builds upon our previously reported <a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2022/06/a-perspective-on-memory-safety.html">Perspective on Memory Safety</a>,
and introduces our strategic approach to memory safety.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/gumt8r">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>security.googleblog.com via tumdum</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T06:32:26.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What are some mind blowing Rust tricks?]]></title>
        <id>14710</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20617271"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T05:52:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What are some mind blowing Rust tricks?]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20617271">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>If we were to create a Rust version of this page for Haskell, what would you add to it?</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20617271">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/little_ferris</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T05:52:03.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smartphone import warning in South Africa]]></title>
        <id>14709</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/smartphones/565324-smartphone-import-warning-in-south-africa.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T06:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smartphone import warning in South Africa]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Africans importing smartphones instead of buying locally could be scoring a good deal, but their devices might not function
as in officially supported countries. Although there are many smartphones available in South Africa from numerous brands and at
various price points, certain models popular elsewhere are not available locally. Among these devices are the Google Pixel and
OnePlus ranges, as well as certain flagship models from locally represented brands like Xiaomi. Many of these smartphones are
available to buy and ship directly from international websites, often at good prices. With more South Africans becoming comfortable
with online shopping and using global e-commerce platforms, there could be a rise in smartphone imports.</p><br/>
<p>Amazon.com makes buying these smartphones straightforward as it includes all shipping and taxes at checkout. However, there are
several drawbacks to be aware of when buying them as opposed to shopping from a reputed local retailer.</p><br/>
<p>The first major issue is that warranty claims could be expensive if a manufacturer does not have local support channels.
If an imported smartphone has a hardware or software defect not caused by the user&#39;s mishandling, it may have to be repaired or
replaced in its country of origin... Buying accessories or replacement parts for devices not widely sold in South Africa will also 
be more difficult or expensive.</p><br/>
<p>The second big catch to look out for is whether the phone is unlocked to be compatible with South African cellular networks.
There may be many instances where a device is restricted to country-specific networks... Fortunately,
sellers on Amazon will clearly indicate if a device is unlocked and capable of working on networks outside the US...</p><br/>
<p>However, even if you have checked the box on network compatibility,
other features may not <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/smartphones/565324-smartphone-import-warning-in-south-africa.html#google-specific-headaches">be supported</a>
or blocked in unofficially supported countries. This is particularly problematic on Google Pixel smartphones -- I recently discovered while importing<br>a Pixel 7 Pro... Although some apps available on the Play Store let users access VoLTE and VoWi-Fi in South Africa,
5G requires rooting or jailbreaking the Pixel, which may restrict access to certain apps and services.[...] Google&#39;s lack of 5G support<br>is unusual because most other Android phones with the capability work in South Africa, regardless of official local availability.[1][2]</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565324">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Hanno Labuschagne</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T06:01:11.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damas-Hindley-Milner inference two ways]]></title>
        <id>14708</id>
        <link href="https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/type-inference/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-15T22:27:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Damas-Hindley-Milner inference two ways]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Max Bernstein has a blog post about implementing Damas-Hindley-Milner (HM) type inference in the programming
language <a href="https://bernsteinbear.com/blog/type-inference/">Scrapscript</a>. From the article:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The core idea in HM is to generate type constraints based on how variables and other expressions are used together
and then solve these constraints. These constraints are based on equality (as opposed to inequality, set subset,
etc). For example, one might look at the expression <code>a+b</code> (where <code>a</code> and <code>b</code> are any expression, but in this case
variables) and deduce that since <code>+</code> is a function that takes two ints and returns an int:</p><br/>
<ul>
<li><code>a</code> must have type int</li>
<li><code>b</code> must have type int</li>
<li><code>a+b</code> must have type int</li>
</ul>
<p>Perhaps, in the same example, later in a function, one might see <code>f a</code> (the application of the variable f to the
argument a) and deduce that f must be a function. We can compose all of these constraints together to infer that f
must be a function that can take an integer as an argument. Similarly, if we saw <code>[a,c]</code> (a list containing elements 
 and c) and we require that our lists have homogeneous type elements, then we can add the constraint that [i]</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The article also explains how they implemented it using Python code.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41853780">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>todsacerdoti</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-15T22:27:17.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LAN: authentication and monitor data consumption]]></title>
        <id>14707</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20616607"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T05:33:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[LAN: authentication and monitor data consumption]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared this summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20616607">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Hi, I would like to create a LAN where each node need to authenticate before gaining access to the LAN. and secondly
be able to monitor the data consumption of each node and even limit the speed for a node when exceeded. I&#39;m looking
for something FLOSS. For example a single-board computer with a gnu/Linux etc... Maybe some distribution or solution
already exist for this ?</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20616607">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://programming.dev/u/Corsair</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T05:33:48.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Problem with green ID books]]></title>
        <id>14706</id>
        <link href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/banking/565460-problem-with-green-id-books.html"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T05:06:54.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Problem with green ID books]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MyBroadband reports:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>A third of Home Affairs offices can&#39;t issue smart ID cards because their systems have not been modernised. Therefore,
South Africa&#39;s old green barcoded ID book remains the only option for many citizens who don&#39;t live near a Home Affairs
or bank branch with the necessary equipment. This is according to home affairs minister Leon Schreiber, who revealed
<a href="https://www.netwerk24.com/netwerk24/stemme/profiele/kyk-ek-wil-jou-id-by-jou-huis-kom-aflewer-se-schreiber-aan-hanlie-20241013">the figure</a>
in an interview with Sunday newspaper Rapport this week. In a separate interview with eNCA, Schreiber
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k7WA5zyUxpE">explained</a> that this is a high-priority challenge because the green ID
book is extremely vulnerable to fraud.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Schreiber said they were looking at ways to expand Home Affairs&#39; presence... The Banking Association of South Africa
(BASA) has been facilitating discussions on public-private partnership (PPP) agreements between the banks and the DHA for about three years. As soon as the PPPs are in place, South Africa&#39;s major banks have told MyBroadband they plan to immediately add 34 additional eHomeAffairs branches to their existing networks. This will more than double the current number of eHomeAffairs branches around the country...  </p><br/>
<p>BASA&#39;s prudential head, Mark Brits, said [the agreements] should be mostly completed and signed by the end of September 2024...</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://mybroadband.co.za/news/?p=565460">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Vermeulen</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>MyBroadband</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T05:06:54.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Medical student's apparent celiac disease responded to giardiasis treatment]]></title>
        <id>14705</id>
        <link href="https://www.backpacker.com/skills/outdoor-first-aid/are-those-stomach-troubles-celiac-or-giardia/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:25:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Medical student's apparent celiac disease responded to giardiasis treatment]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from Backpacker:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Anders Johnson hadn&#39;t eaten gluten in nearly a decade. After coming down with an unidentifiable illness in the summer
of 2006 while running high adventure trips at a Boy Scout camp in Southern California, he had been wracked with serious
gastrointestinal dysfunction distress, depression, and brain fog. No matter how much he ate, he kept losing weight.
At one point, he logged his caloric intake for a college nutrition class and found that he had been eating seven thousand
calories a day, despite looking sickly thin. Around Thanksgiving of that year, it got so bad Johnson had to go to an
urgent care because he was so dehydrated. &quot;I ended up failing a good chunk of my classes that semester just because I
didn&#39;t have any energy,&quot; Johnson says.&quot;Then I started hitting the doctors really hard, trying to figure it out.&quot;  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Johnson&#39;s results came back borderline; not definitively positive, but not exactly negative either. He ran with it.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;I started eating gluten-free. I started regaining mental faculties and started getting a little bit of weight back on
me,&quot; Johnson says &quot;Whenever I cheated, it would just throw me back into a downward spiral.&quot; But doctors never definitively diagnosed Johnson with celiac disease... In 2015,
however... <a href="https://www.backpacker.com/survival/natural-hazards/backpackers-usually-fear-the-wrong-things/">a college friend who&#39;d had</a> [...] texted Johnson that she had eaten [...] cookie.
As it turned out,[...] what that friend had assumed was celiac disease was [a\ very\ different\ illness:\ giardia\ (an<br>easily-treatable intestinal parasite)]. The chronic form of giardiasis is lesser known, however. The friend sent\nJohnson medical studies showing how chronic Giardia infection can cause celiac-like symptoms.[&quot;It was like a whole bunch of puzzle pieces fell into place at the same time,&quot;]</p><br/>
<p>said Johnson.</p><br/>
<p>The issue was that he kept testing negative for giardiasis. Johnson wasn&#39;t convinced.</p><br/>
<p>Johnson took pictures of his sample, along with the commercial one, and presented them to a doctor. ... Instead, the doctor prescribed him <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC10004567/">a cocktail</a> [of antibiotics,
antifungals,\ and antiprotozoal medications]. &quot;If my intestines were warzone, we went full nuclear,&quot; Johnson remarked.\nA few weeks after the last round of medication, ... On the first round, after waiting 24 hours to see if he would have\n[...] reaction, ...</p><br/>
<p>He could eat gluten again...</p><br/>
<p>Dr. Leo Galland/span&gt;, <a href="https://leogalland.com/about-dr-galland/">a doctor</a> [of internal medicine-based practice focused on functional medicine/span&gt;], describes people like Anders\nJohnson as having non-celiac gluten intolerance from chronic giardiasis.... Dr Galland also says that giardiasis can be hard to get accurate results for as well.... Chronic giardia,...can be particularly hard to identify....</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855307">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BostonFern</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:25:14.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let Google Decide]]></title>
        <id>14704</id>
        <link href="https://cupofsquid.com/post/not-real/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T04:07:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let Google Decide]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shares a summary from <a href="https://cupofsquid.com/post/not-real/">Cup of Squid</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>My partner and I recently moved states in order to benefit from lower rent and a more affordable living
environment. We found a place on Craigslist for the winter that was not only scam-free, but extremely cute. We
visited it in person, met the landlord, and agreed to tenancy until April after the threat of frost. The process,
despite its rushed quality, was rather straightforward.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855512">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>lr0</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T04:07:22.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A deep dive into the iOS backup/restore system: The Sparserestore exploit]]></title>
        <id>14703</id>
        <link href="https://gist.github.com/leminlimez/c602c067349140fe979410ef69d39c28"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T04:50:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A deep dive into the iOS backup/restore system: The Sparserestore exploit]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of the writeups reverse engineering the iOS backup system are outdated and do not necessarily represent how it works
in modern day. They also tended to describe the structure of a backup file, but do not detail the on-device process of
restoring a backup behind the scenes. The goal of this writeup is to document my findings on the backup system over the
years and what I learned while developing <a href="https://github.com/leminlimez/CowabungaLite">Cowabunga Lite</a> and <a href="https://github.com/leminlimez/Nugget-Mobile">Nugget</a>. I will also be covering <a href="/leminlimez/c602c067349140fe979410ef69d39c28#sparserestore">the Sparserestore exploit</a>.</p><br/>
<p>There is not a lot of documentation of how the backup domains map to the iOS file system, so I am compiling what I found
here.</p><br/>
<p><strong>What is a domain?</strong> In a backup, domains tell iOS what files to restore and where. It is both a way of organization and
a security measure. Having domains prevents attackers from using restores to write anywhere in the file system.</p><br/>
<p>There are 2 different kinds of domains:</p><br/>
<ol>
<li><p>The main type of domain is simply mapped to a file path (e.g., <code>HomeDomain</code> = <code>/var/mobile</code>) with some restrictions.</p><br/>
</li>
<li><p>The second type requires an extension: <code>SysContainerDomain</code>, <code>SysSharedContainerDomain</code>, or <code>AppDomain</code>. These have
trailing dashes (<code>-</code>) where their extensions go; for example:</p><br/>
<ul>
<li><p>For <code>SysContainerDomain</code> or <code>SysSharedContainerDomain</code>, it&#39;s after that dash.</p><br/>
</li>
<li><p>For AppDomains, it&#39;s after that dash + app bundle ID.</p><br/>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<blockquote>
<p>Outside of [the domain itself], [the path] will act like regular domains... There used to be a file in /System/Library/Backup/domains.plist that listed many paths &amp; what could be backed up, but it was removed in iOS 17,
seemingly correlated to separating /var &amp; /var/mobile partitions... A markdown version can be found in Domains.md if you would like more about what can &amp; cannot be restored in each domain.[...]</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The article goes into much greater detail about Apple&#39;s changes made with its latest OS update — including &quot;many modifications&quot; made specifically for backups — as well as details about restoring specific types data such as media,
preferences, health information etc.</p><br/>
<p>But perhaps most interestingly they discuss an exploit called <strong>Sparserestore</strong>, which allowed users &quot;to continuously go back&quot; through directories until reaching root level access:</p><br/>
<p>&quot;The Sparserestore exploit is very simple at its core,&quot; writes developer Lemin Limez on GitHub:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>It uses backpathing [..] allowing you write anywhere on <code>/var</code> partition that&#39;s not SSV protected.... After -, you are currently in directory: <code>/private/var/.backup.i/var/root/Library/Backup/SystemContainers/Data/... This your starting path... Once you reach root\, you can place any filepath afterwards.... At end restore\, we crash by restoring directly </code>/private`.
Normally, crash cancel would no files change. However, using exploit, files still restored. This has added benefit skipping setup entirely without having modify files like Cowabunga Lite...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Apple patched this vulnerability last year during beta testing for its next major release (i.e., iOS 18), restricting all
domains from containing slashes (&quot;/&quot;).  </p><br/>
<p>You can read more here (or check out Limez&#39;s full post via his GitHub page):</p><br/>
<p><a href="https://gist.github.com/leminlimez/c602c067349140fe979410ef69d39c28">A deep dive into the iOS backup/restore system · GitHub</a></p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/sgyfdg">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>gist.github.com via eBPF</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T04:50:34.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Popups and Menus in Qt Quick 6.8]]></title>
        <id>14702</id>
        <link href="https://www.qt.io/blog/popups-and-menus-in-qt-quick-6.8"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T04:18:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Popups and Menus in Qt Quick 6.8]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Qt Quick 6.8 introduces the ability to create top-level popups, dialogs, tooltips, and menus in dedicated windows using a new
<code>popupType</code> property. This feature allows developers to achieve a more native desktop application experience similar to Qt
Widgets applications.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Up until now, the only way to achieve the same kind of top-level popup windows in Qt Quick, were to create custom
components based on Window... In Qt 6.8, it&#39;s finally possible to have Popup, Dialogs, ToolTips, and Menus inside
top-level windows. This can be controlled by the new <code>popupType</code> property...  </p><br/>
<p>Windows also supports native WIN32 context menus [that] might appear somewhat outdated, and Popup.Window can be used
instead, for a more consistent look on modern platforms... On macOS, we&#39;ve finally added support for native menu bars!
You will never have to choose between the <code>QtQuick.Controls</code> and <code>Qt.labs.platform</code> menu bars ever again...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/u3whcy">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>qt.io via raymii</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T04:18:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rebooting the Arsenal of Democracy]]></title>
        <id>14701</id>
        <link href="https://www.rebootingthearsenal.com/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T02:46:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rebooting the Arsenal of Democracy]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Xi Jinping believes he can out-innovate American defense. Is he right? <a href="https://www.rebootingthearsenal.com/">Palmer Luckey</a>,
founder of Anduril Industries, thinks not. &quot;There is no secret government silo of advanced technology that will save us if
war breaks out,&quot; writes Luckey in a blog post. &quot;You must build it.&quot; From the article:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>If you have read this far, you care deeply about the future of our collective defense. Help us to reboot the arsenal of
democracy and make that future safe, prosperous, and free.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855117">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>bear_with_me</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T02:46:29.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[National Archives Pushes Google Gemini AI on Employees]]></title>
        <id>14700</id>
        <link href="https://www.404media.co/ai-mazing-tech-venture-national-archives-pushes-google-gemini-ai-on-employees/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:36:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[National Archives Pushes Google Gemini AI on Employees]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In June, the U.S. National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) gave employees a presentation and tech demo called
<a href="https://www.404media.co/ai-mazing-tech-venture-national-archives-pushes-google-gemini-ai-on-employees/">&quot;AI-mazing Tech-venture&quot;</a>
in which Google&#39;s Gemini AI was presented as a tool archives employees could use to &quot;enhance productivity.&quot; During a demo,
the AI was queried with questions about the John F. Kennedy assassination, according to <a href="https://www.404media.co/ai-mazing-tech-venture-national-archives-pushes-google-gemini-ai-on-employees/">a copy of the presentation
obtained by 404 Media using a public records
request</a>. In
December, NARA plans to launch a public-facing AI-powered chatbot called &quot;Archie AI,&quot; 404 Media has learned.</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>&quot;The National Archives has big plans for AI,&quot; <a href="https://www.404media.co/ai-mazing-tech-venture-national-archives-pushes-google-gemini-ai-on-employees/">a NARA spokesperson told 404 Media</a>. &quot;It&#39;s going to be essential to how we conduct our work, how we scale our services for Americans who want to be able to access our records from anywhere, anytime,
and how we ensure that we are ready to care for the records being created today and in the future.&quot;</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Employee chat logs given during the presentation show that National Archives employees are concerned about the idea that AI
tools will be used in archiving, a practice that is inherently concerned with accurately recording history.</p><br/>
<p>One worker who attended the presentation told 404 Media “I suspect they&#39;re going to introduce it [Gemini] into workplace.
I&#39;m just a person who works there and hates [AI] bullshit.” The presentation was given about a month after NARA banned
employees from using ChatGPT because it said it posted an “unacceptable risk&quot; [to data security], and cautioned them not
to rely on LLMs for factual information...  </p><br/>
<p>During the demonstration of Google’s Vertex AI — which allows organizations like NARA train large language models on their own datasets — one employee asked: “How would [the] public know they are receiving response from actual archivist or not generative A.I.? Would N.A.R.A disclose what aspects of reference are generated from A.I?” Two other employees followed up saying they were also concerned this might lower trust in institution if not properly disclosed...</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855366">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>m463</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:36:36.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plutocrat Archipelagos]]></title>
        <id>14699</id>
        <link href="https://www.macguffinmagazine.com/stories/macguffin-plutocrat-archipelagos"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:08:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plutocrat Archipelagos]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long-time Slashdot reader <a href="https://www.jones-supa.com/">jones_supa</a> shares a report from MacGuffin Magazine:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Razor wire fences, galvanized spikes and electrified perimeters: the barriers that entomb the ultra-rich in their walled
settlements isolate them from perpetual violence and societal collapse.  </p><br/>
<p>I have had the opportunity to meet a surprisingly large number of ultra-high net worth individuals over the years -- not
through any particular personal desire, I hasten to add. A few of these people I&#39;ve merely met in passing, typically at
some event held by a cultural institution. However, I have come to know several others quite well, as either friends or
as employers. (I am specifically speaking about four of the world&#39;s 2,781 billionaires).  </p><br/>
<p>Regardless of whether they are &#39;self made&#39; or &#39;second gen&#39;, the ultra-rich have unique psychological profiles amongst
the general populace. In my experience, both categories of billionaire are dominated by interminable existential crises --
although each displays nuance when it comes to confrontation. The &#39;self made&#39; have a tendency towards aggressive
megalomania, while &#39;second gens&#39; demur in favour of nihilistic hedonism.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The article goes on to describe how &quot;the unjustifiably wealthy are unfit for rule,&quot; adding that &quot;it is impossible for such people to go on holiday.&quot; From there:</p><br/>
<p>\begin{quote}<br>We are living through a period of societal collapse... We are living through the most dangerous phase of modernity,
when those in power will do anything they can to preserve an increasingly fragile status quo... Perhaps as modernity gives way 
to the next paradigm (we are already in a new Renaissance), there will not be more or less violence than under late capitalism.
This might mean that [...] we might not see [...] uncontrolled climate migration largely assumed to accompany 
the collapse [...]. On the other hand, although [...] it may well be that only descendants inherit Earth.\end{quote}</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41855217">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>bookofjoe</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:08:01.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Petroleum Drilling Technology Is Now Making Carbon-Free Power]]></title>
        <id>14698</id>
        <link href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/15/2331231/petroleum-drilling-technology-is-now-making-carbon-free-power?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&amp;utm_medium=feed"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Petroleum Drilling Technology Is Now Making Carbon-Free Power]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from NPR:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>There&#39;s a valley in rural southwest Utah that&#39;s become a hub for renewable energy. Dozens of tall white wind turbines
whoosh up in the sky. A sea of solar panels glistens in the distance. But the new kid on the block is mostly hidden
underground. From the surface, Fervo Energy&#39;s Cape Station looks more or less like an oil derrick, with a thin metal
tower rising above the sagebrush steppe. But this $2 billion geothermal project, which broke ground last year, is not
drilling for gas. It&#39;s drilling for underground heat that CEO Tim Latimer believes holds <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/10/15/nx-s1-5035523/petroleum-drilling-technology-carbon-free-power">the key to generating carbon-free power</a> -- lots of it.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;Just these three well pads alone will produce 100 megawatts of electricity,&quot; he said. &quot;Around-the-clock, 24/7
electricity.&quot; Latimer stood overlooking the project, which is currently under construction, on one of the drill rig&#39;s
metal platforms 40 feet off the ground...  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>The U.S Department of Energy found that geothermal energy could provide up to <a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2019/06/f63/GeoVision-full-report-opt.pdf">120 gigawatts</a> (or about 16% percent) of America&#39;s anticipated electricity needs by 2050.</p><br/>
<p>But traditional technologies can only be deployed economically in areas where underground heat is easily accessible,
according to Google and Fervo co-founder Tim Latimer.</p><br/>
<p>&quot;That&#39;s not a statement you could have made two or three years ago,&quot; he said...<br>Fervo signed <a href="https://fervoenergy.com/fervo-energy-announces-320-mw-power-purchase-agreements-with-southern-california-edison/">a landmark deal</a>
with Southern California Edison this summer; it will send its first batch of geothermal juice to SoCal Edison&#39;s grid in
2026...</p><br/>
<p>California leaders set a mandate in 2018 requiring [...] <strong>100%</strong> renewable electricity by [...]. SoCal Edison spokesperson Reggie Kumar said adding geothermal makes sense: &quot;For California to achieve its decarbonization goals by [2045], we need more clean firm resources.&quot;</p><br/>
<p>The article also notes how enhanced geothermal systems are being pioneered at Utah FORGE (Frontier Observatory for Research
in Geothermal Energy), funded with $220 million from DOE back in 2018:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The mission isn&#39;t to produce its own electricity; it&#39;s to test tools and techniques through trial and error and answer <br>the big question: Can you pipe cool water through cracks in hot underground rock and create a geothermal plant almost<br>anywhere? That idea is known as an enhanced geothermal system... Six years after drilling began,[...] they proved for<br>the first time they could pump water from one well, through underground cracks, into another well...</p><br/>
<p>Other than creating those cracks, McLennan said, there would be no significant difference between what they&#39;re doing<br>at FORGE today versus what oil companies were doing here decades ago when they were looking for fossil fuels...</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://hardware.slashdot.org/story/24/10/15/2331231/petroleum-drilling-technology-is-now-making-carbon-free-power?utm_source=atom1.0mainlinkanon&utm_medium=feed">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>BeauHD</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Slashdot</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:30:00.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenTelemetry Challenges: Handling Long-Running Spans]]></title>
        <id>14697</id>
        <link href="https://hazelweakly.me/blog/opentelemetry-challenges-handling-long-running-spans/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:25:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[OpenTelemetry Challenges: Handling Long-Running Spans]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long-running spans are one of my biggest &quot;we don&#39;t really actually have a good standard solution for this&quot; issues in
opentelemetry. They&#39;re something I&#39;ve run into before, weirdly frequently, and especially so when attempting to try and
instrument front-end or mobile facing systems. It turns out, though, that the issues here with long running spans are
actually pretty similar to the issues with interrupted, partial, or unclosed spans. In fact, they&#39;re really mostly the
same thing (with the added bonus that if you do tail sampling your sampling decision is going to happen before the span
ends, which exacerbates the problem by turning functioning spans into partial and broken ones) [writes Hazel Weakly at The New Stack].</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Anyway, I talk about this and more in this article and even point out a really cool solution from Embrace that addresses this in an opentelemetry compatible way (hint: does the phrase &quot;write ahead log&quot; make you quiver with excitement? If so,
you should definitely read this).  </p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/dqhxsc">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>hazelweakly.me via jaywhy13</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:25:04.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Break it up! Improving Your Godot Code Using Components]]></title>
        <id>14696</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20614121"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T02:59:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Break it up! Improving Your Godot Code Using Components]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader shared a summary from <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20614121">programming.dev</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>Here&#39;s a tutorial I wrote on using components to help keep your code organized.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20614121">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://lemmy.one/u/TheLongPrice</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T02:59:44.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to UX/RT (2022)]]></title>
        <id>14695</id>
        <link href="https://archive.fosdem.org/2022/schedule/event/awarkentin/attachments/slides/4831/export/events/attachments/awarkentin/slides/4831/uxrt_intro.pdf"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T03:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to UX/RT (2022)]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An anonymous reader quotes a report from Slashdot:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="https://archive.fosdem.org/2022/">FOSDEM 2022 conference</a> featured a talk titled &quot;Introduction to UX/RT,&quot; which
discussed the intersection of user experience (UX) and real-time systems (RT). In this presentation, Alexander Warkentin
explained how these two fields can work together to create better software. He also shared some examples of projects that
have successfully integrated UX and RT principles.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/cpncvm">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>archive.fosdem.org via m0th</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T03:00:22.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SeleneCMS - Content Management for Symfony]]></title>
        <id>14693</id>
        <link href="https://programming.dev/post/20613516"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T02:27:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SeleneCMS - Content Management for Symfony]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SeleneCMS is a content management system built as a Symfony bundle. The developer <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20613516">is looking for contributors to help
expand its features</a>, and has just uploaded version 0.0.12 with plans for 0.0.13.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://programming.dev/post/20613516">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>https://lemmy.world/u/psion1369</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>programming.dev - Local</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T02:27:11.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the Richest People Can Access Billions Without Selling Their Stock]]></title>
        <id>14692</id>
        <link href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnhyatt/2021/11/11/how-americas-richest-people-larry-ellison-elon-musk-can-access-billions-without-selling-their-stock/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T01:23:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How the Richest People Can Access Billions Without Selling Their Stock]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of the country’s richest people, including Elon Musk and Larry Ellison, borrow against their stock while avoiding
capital gains taxes. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnhyatt/2021/11/11/how-americas-richest-people-larry-ellison-elon-musk-can-access-billions-without-selling-their-stock/">Forbes reports</a> on how this works:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>When the world’s richest man wants cash, he can simply borrow money by putting up -- or pledging -- some of his Tesla
shares as collateral for lines of credit, instead of selling shares and paying capital gains taxes. These pledged
shares serve as an evergreen credit facility, giving Musk access to cash when he needs it. Musk currently has pledged
88.3 million Tesla shares, nearly 36.2% of his overall stake (excluding options), as of Wednesday worth more than $94
billion.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>Musk is one of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/forbes-400/">32 billionaires identified in the Forbes 400 list</a> who are pledging public stock as collateral for current or potential lines of credit; others include Oracle chairman Larry Ellison,
Walmart heir Jim Walton and private equity&#39;s Stephen Schwarzman.</p><br/>
<p>Across all companies listed on the NYSE and Nasdaq exchanges, there are 560 executive officers and directors and 5%+
shareholders currently pledging shares; the size of the average pledge is $427 million and the aggregate value of these
pledged shares is $239 billion...  </p><br/>
<p>Most larger companies don&#39;t allow pledging: Over two-thirds (68.4%) of S&amp;P 500 companies ban all company employees and shareholders from pledging shares for debt...</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41854749">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>CHB0403085482</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T01:23:46.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Correct eye contact in videos by redirecting the eyes to look at the camera]]></title>
        <id>14691</id>
        <link href="https://www.sievedata.com/functions/sieve/eye-contact-correction"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T01:37:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Correct eye contact in videos by redirecting the eyes to look at the camera]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sieve&#39;s Eye Contact Correction API is a fast and high-quality eye contact correction API built for developers. Eye
contact correction is a technique for ensuring that the eyes in a video appear to be looking at the camera, even when
the subject is not actually looking at it. This is achieved by redirecting the eyes to simulate eye contact with the
camera.</p><br/>
<p>The <a href="https://www.sievedata.com/functions/sieve/eye-contact-correction">Eye Contact Correction API</a> can correct gaze in
videos while preserving original blinking and head movements, allowing you to create more natural-looking videos.
Pricing starts at $0.10 per minute of video processed.</p><br/>
<p>Here&#39;s how Sieve describes its technology:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The input must be a video file (image files are not supported). Processing time depends on the video length and
resolution; longer or higher-resolution videos will take more time to process. The <code>accuracy_boost</code> option provides
more precise results but may increase processing time as well.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<p>For any issues or questions, please get in touch with <a href="mailto:contact@sievedata.com">contact@sievedata.com</a>.</p><br/>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41854801">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>thunderbong</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Hacker News Front Page</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T01:37:12.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rogue Legacy code is now source available]]></title>
        <id>14690</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/flibitijibibo/RogueLegacy1/"/>
        <updated>2024-10-16T02:31:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rogue Legacy code is now source available]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rogue Legacy&#39;s source code is now available on <a href="https://github.com/flibitijibibo/RogueLegacy1/">GitHub</a>, reports
<a href="https://games.slashdot.org/story/23/10/05/2150244/rogue-legacy-code-is-now-source-available">Slashdot</a>:</p><br/>
<blockquote>
<p>The assets and contentproj are not included. From the project&#39;s README: &quot;Rogue Legacy&#39;s source code is released under a
specialized, non-commercial-use license.&quot; See LICENSE.md for details.</p><br/>
</blockquote>
<br/><hr/>
                <a href="https://lobste.rs/s/hj0ab1">Comments</a>
                | <a href="https://refeedr.inmytrees.co.za/?id=undefined&url=">View Source</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>github.com via Decabytes</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Lobsters</name>
        </author>
        <published>2024-10-16T02:31:18.000Z</published>
    </entry>
</feed>